<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title><![CDATA[Lian Liu]]></title>
  <subtitle><![CDATA[Learn more about me]]></subtitle>
  <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://lianliu.me/"/>
  <updated>2015-01-14T02:57:12.968Z</updated>
  <id>http://lianliu.me/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Lian.Liu]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[durianl1988@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="http://zespia.tw/hexo/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Comic Book in New York]]></title>
    <link href="http://lianliu.me/2015/01/09/Comic-Book-in-New-York/"/>
    <id>http://lianliu.me/2015/01/09/Comic-Book-in-New-York/</id>
    <published>2015-01-10T03:53:42.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-01-14T02:27:47.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In many ways, New York city is quite like Shanghai. The skyscrapers drop your hat when you try to count the floors; the crowd pushes you to move no matter you want or not; the luxury brands shine in windows innocently towards tourists from all around the world; the traffic is always terrible in downtown area; people with different backgrounds and religions gather in their own group but get along with each others as well.<br>I do enjoy the clear blue sky here, which is becoming more and more rare in Shanghai these years. If ignoring some of the old, sticky, creepy subway stations, this should be a nice city to live in.<br>Anyway, I properly used my imaginations to the pictures taken in New York city. Or there would be no fun at all to show those monotonous METROPOLISES images.<br>By the way, super fan of Marvel here :)</p>
<p><img src="http://ww4.sinaimg.cn/mw690/72a818edjw1eo48m0oghnj20sg0lcwk3.jpg" alt="spiderman1"></p>
<p><img src="http://ww2.sinaimg.cn/mw690/72a818edjw1eo48mjqbtsj20lc0sgq9r.jpg" alt="spiderman2"></p>
<p><img src="http://ww1.sinaimg.cn/mw690/72a818edjw1eo48nbk7auj20sg0lc77q.jpg" alt="loki"></p>
<p><img src="http://ww3.sinaimg.cn/mw690/72a818edjw1eo48nfge9hj20lc0sgaev.jpg" alt="thor"></p>
<p><img src="http://ww1.sinaimg.cn/mw690/72a818edjw1eo48mt3fysj20lc0sggqc.jpg" alt="hawkeye"></p>
<p><img src="http://ww3.sinaimg.cn/mw690/72a818edjw1eo48ma28rij20sg0lcjwj.jpg" alt="baymax1"></p>
<p><img src="http://ww3.sinaimg.cn/mw690/72a818edjw1eo48lt8bfmj20lc0sggqw.jpg" alt="baymax2"></p>
<p><img src="http://ww3.sinaimg.cn/mw690/72a818edjw1eo48lofrd4j20lc0sg0x4.jpg" alt="hulk"></p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>In many ways, New York city is quite like Shanghai. The skyscrapers drop your hat when you try to count the floors; the crowd pushes you ]]>
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Color" scheme="http://lianliu.me/tags/Color/"/>
    
      <category term="Travel" scheme="http://lianliu.me/tags/Travel/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Project Management Case Study]]></title>
    <link href="http://lianliu.me/2014/11/05/Project-Management-Case-Study/"/>
    <id>http://lianliu.me/2014/11/05/Project-Management-Case-Study/</id>
    <published>2014-11-05T17:03:30.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-01-14T02:55:51.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="CHRYSLER_AND_BMW:_TRITEC_ENGINE_JOINT_VENTURE_(Section)">CHRYSLER AND BMW: TRITEC ENGINE JOINT VENTURE (Section)</h1>
<p><strong>Created by</strong><br>Master of Engineering Management Program, Duke University<br>Class of 2013<br>Akash Gupta, Aaron Shakin<br>Class of 2014<br>Mohammad Ali Raahim, Lian Liu</p>
<h2 id="Executive_Summary">Executive Summary</h2>
<p>Our team was contracted by Tritec, a team formed by the joint venture between Chrysler and BMW to select an appropriate solution for the engine block sealing design. The purpose of the joint venture was to capitalize on the opportunities in Asia and Latin America for low cost engines ranging in size from 1.0 – 1.6 liters. After discussing, the joint team decided to establish an engine plant in Brazil, as Chrysler believed other emerging countries were too risky and the overall project would be led by Jack Smith.<br>Our team needed to analyze and resolve the differences between the product engineering and the advanced manufacturing team. The advanced manufacturing team believed that the lower tie bar design selected by the product engineering team is impractical, as it would necessitate reinventing part of the machining process, which would be difficult.<br>We used a four-fold method to define success and select the best design. Based on our findings, our recommendation is the bedplate design, since it proved to be the most favorable option in three of these five categories.<br>… …</p>
<h2 id="Project_Charter">Project Charter</h2>
<p>Approval: The proposed plan would need a formal approval from the Tritec Management. Approval will depend on the feasibility of the analysis presented in the report and the consent of the product engineering and advanced manufacturing teams who are primary stakeholders.<br>Resources: The resources for development of each selected project type will be assigned based on approval from management. Additional resources could be assigned subject to approval and requirement.<br>Project Manager: The Project Manager (PM) for the joint venture between BMW and Chrysler is Jack Smith. He is considered a talented manufacturing engineer with advanced degrees in mechanical engineering. He was concerned about his lack of experience but the management assured him he would be provided with necessary resources.</p>
<h3 id="Problem_Statement">Problem Statement</h3>
<p><strong>Current State:</strong> Tritec is currently facing a dilemma with regard to the engine block design. The product engineering team believed that a lower tie bar design would help decrease anticipated warranty costs and would be more reliable, while the advanced manufacturing team believed that this design would necessitate the reinvention of the machining process which would create an added challenge.<br>Future State: We envision that the selected design will satisfy both the product engineering team and the advanced manufacturing engineering team based on the thorough analysis. The chosen design would also help Tritec develop an engine that would make the joint venture achieve profitable growth with less risk.<br><strong>Constraints:</strong> The limitations of risk, design feasibility and future impact were among the constraints considered.  Time and budget are perhaps the most important constraints in this endeavor.  There are check points to gauge progress throughout the building process of the engines, but ultimately, it is imperative for Tritec to implement a sealing design that helps achieve its  mission of building “the world’s lowest overall cost engine business in the city of Campo Largo, Brazil by July 2000” (mission idea is from Team 8’s report; quote from page 8 of the case). </p>
<h2 id="Design_Selection_Approach">Design Selection Approach</h2>
<p>The design selection approach was based on a number of metrics. In order to arrive at the recommended design, a comparative analysis was carried out to weigh the strengths and weaknesses of each design. Using this approach, the first order of business was to define an empirical criteria/definition for a successful design within the constraints of the Tritec team’s design and manufacturing capabilities. Keeping the available data in mind, the following criteria were defined:</p>
<ol>
<li>Conformance/positive impact on the 12-panel objectives</li>
<li>Design favorability, in terms of investment, variable cost, manufacturing, workload etc.</li>
<li>Sealing design and process risk</li>
<li>Warranty assessment<br>The design that performed best on the above set of criteria was deemed as the most suitable one for the project team to pursue.<br>Conformance/positive impact on the 12-panel objectives<br>Exhibit 18 scored each design approach on the 12-panel objectives spelled out to gauge the progress of the project. The original tie bar design served as the reference, while the two alternatives either got a 0 (indicating performance at-par with the original design), a positive (indicating a relative advantage) or a negative (indicating a relative disadvantage) on each of the 12 objectives.<br>In our approach, we summed up the impact ratings to arrive at a final score for each design. By default, the original tie bar design had a score of 0, while analysis of the other two designs revealed the following:<br>•    Bedplate design had a score of -1<br>•    Rear retainer style had a score of -4<br>•    Conclusion: In terms of positive impact on the 12-panel objectives, the original tie bar design performed the best with a score of 0. The bedplate design, however, was a close second.<h3 id="Design_favorability">Design favorability</h3>
Next, each of the designs was evaluated on the basis of favorability. The data was obtained from Exhibit 17. A higher summary total score indicated more favorability. The number was obtained by taking a weighted sum of the ratings assigned to each design approach based on a number of practical implementation aspects. The following results were gleaned from the data:<br>•    Bedplate design had the highest summary total of 158, followed by the rear retainer style design with 137<br>•    Conclusion: Bedplate design has the most favorable design review</li>
</ol>
<p>… …</p>
<h3 id="Assumptions_used_in_the_approach">Assumptions used in the approach</h3>
<ol>
<li>It was assumed that the 4.7L comparison of bore centers and access issues will not reveal any risk, thus arriving at a total process risk score of 682 for the bedplate design. As the design in question was not the leading performer in this category, the assumption did not have any impact on the result. </li>
<li>The “?” for the timing objective in Exhibit 18 was assumed to have a value of 0. Again, assuming it was either an advantage or disadvantage would not have had any impact on the conclusion derived from the 12-panel criterion.</li>
<li>The supplier tooling cost in the case of bedplate is assumed to be the same as the other two designs ($307,000).</li>
<li>The variable costs remain the same for each of the five years considered in the cost analysis.<br>Evaluation of Project Procedure and Management Process </li>
</ol>
<h2 id="Management_Group">Management Group</h2>
<p>The management group from the very beginning of this project lacked effective communication and interactive approaches with team members. More often than not, the team members were speculating the reasons for unexpected results, instead of being involved in the decision making. For example, Chrysler held the very first meeting with BMW before the team reached to any other companies. BMW Board Director Dr. Reitzle, then accepted Chrysler’s proposal despite the objectives from his engineers.<br>These assertive decisions brought some unforeseen trouble when proceeding with the project. As we can see now, the successor team was not satisfied with the outcome from the predecessor team, since their opinion was not considered thoroughly. Additionally, the overlooking of team members’ comments reduced their loyalty to the company and consequently compromised the prestige of the management group. </p>
<h3 id="Team_Structure_and_Management">Team Structure and Management</h3>
<p>From Exhibits 5, 6 and 7 we can tell that, although each company accounted for half of the Joint Venture Steering Committee, more than two thirds of the Tritec staff leaders were from Chrysler, further imbalanced by recent staff recruits. This skewed organization chart meant that when the committee was negotiating the proposal for reaching an agreement beneficial to both sides, the implementation would likely face resistance from the execution teams either due to the different interests or different corporate cultures.<br>Another considerable problem from the team structure was that most of the execution team leaders had ten years or even more than twenty years of experience in this field, while the project manager, Jack Smith was only 33 years old and had been recently selected to run Chrysler’s van assembly plant. This disparity in experience would make it difficult for the project manager to have his decisions carried out effectively. Chrysler did provide Smith with experienced people in this project as promised, but their experience may not be entirely beneficial with a young project manager. </p>
<h3 id="Project_Manager">Project Manager</h3>
<p>Some issues regarding the project manager’s fit with this joint venture and his approach to situations he encountered may have inhibited the ability of the project to run seamlessly.  To begin with, the project manager, Jack Smith was not involved in this project until November 1996, which was almost one year after the first meeting between Chrysler and BMW. Before he joined, the engineers from both teams had already gone through some of the design details and reached an agreement to some extent. The project manager’s absence from the early period of a project led to inadequate understanding of the project’s scope. Despite the fact that Smith joined the project shortly before the agreement was signed, it still took substantial time for him to become familiar with the team and their ideas. To a certain degree, this resulted in subsequent conflicts and inefficient communication afterwards.<br>Furthermore, in a cross-functional team, especially one that has members from two companies with different corporate cultures, the project manager is particularly responsible for the team’s collaboration as well as project control. Although Smith had education and plant experience in mechanical engineering, he lacked sufficient capability in running large, complex operations. The approaches he adopted to manage the team, such as the creation of a Tritec contract book and having many meetings and workshops were techniques based on coping with ideal circumstances, without consideration of the actual situation. The revisions of the contract book proved that Smith was willing to allow proper evaluations and corresponding adjustments according to the feedback; but undoubtedly this protracted delivery had lost much of the impact on some early design decisions. </p>
<h3 id="Suggested_Actions_for_Successful_Implementation">Suggested Actions for Successful Implementation</h3>
<p>In view of the above mentioned facts, and to ensure this project moves forward smoothly, we have four suggestions for procedures and management processes as follows.</p>
<ol>
<li>Make a decision of the sealing design as soon as possible. Since points of view have been expressed sufficiently, a final decision is possible with mutual understanding using the detailed analysis demonstrated above. </li>
<li>Explore a more effective communication approach between the management group and the execution teams. Instead of frequent dogmatic meetings, the management should pay more attention to their employees and make sure the decisions are understood by everyone involved. </li>
<li>Improve the team dynamics, especially for the interaction between the Advanced Manufacturing Engineering team and the other engineers. Moving the team off-site in the middle of the project is not a good first option; but technology and commuting support can be optimized if it is needed. </li>
<li>Support the current project manager with team alignment by providing the assistance of a senior employee with more practical experience in cross-functional team management. </li>
</ol>
<h2 id="Risks_and_Best_Practices_for_Addressing_Them">Risks and Best Practices for Addressing Them</h2>
<p>While the bedplate design appears to have more advantages than the other two alternatives, it does not come without risks and potential drawbacks.  One of these risks is the condensed time frame for redesigning the lower end of the engine block.  To overcome this risk, staff would need to be reallocated to concentrate on designing in order to meet the “OK to tool” milestone. Reassigning individuals to design roles who have minimal training and experience presents another risk.  Therefore, project manager, Jack Smith should also consider hiring new employees specialized in design.  While it would be costly to hire new designers to help accelerate this stage, there still is an estimated $5 million in reserve, which could be put towards bringing on extra staff to compensate for lost time.<br>The bedplate design comes with an added $8 million involved in bedplate machining that is not required for the other two designs.  Bedplate machining would also entail two extra assembly lines in the machining process which increases the amount of interdependency involved and the likelihood of delays.  Tritec can attempt to find a reliable subcontractor to machine the bedplate at a lower cost than Tritec would otherwise have, for purchasing the extra machining equipment and doing the machining of the bedplate themselves.  Finding a vendor that already has the necessary equipment for making the bedplate and experienced machinists with this step, would alleviate risks involved in bedplate manufacturing and eliminate one of the added assembly lines, as long as there would not be any excessive delays involved for order processing and shipping time.<br>Another risk involved in the investment for the bedplate is the unknown cost of supplier tooling.  As shown in Exhibit 13, the supplier tooling is listed as “TBD” for the bedplate while the other two designs have costs of $307,000.  To address the risk involved in this uncertain expense, Tritec must determine approximate costs for supplier tooling options that are available, and then make a conservative estimate based on this data, so that the expense can be factored into the projected investment.  If the cost is on the same order of magnitude as the supplier tooling costs for the other two design alternatives, then it will not have a significant impact on the total investment, and there would still be some reserve funds remaining.</p>
<h2 id="Lessons_Learned">Lessons Learned</h2>
<p>This case was invaluable to us because of the added stipulation of not being able to communicate face to face with teammates.  Since many project teams and consulting companies have individuals in different locations, meetings where all members are physically present are not always practical, particularly for tasks that can be orchestrated remotely.  We treated this process similarly to the how we conducted previous team meetings for prior cases, except in this situation, our meetings were done through Google Hangout sessions.  While it seemed as though this requirement would present an extra challenge, we felt that we could still turn in quality work, as we had before.  In some respects, meeting remotely made it less of a challenge to arrange meetings, since all group members did not need to be in the same location.<br>Having a few weeks available to complete this assignment, we found it advantageous to make the most of the time available.  On previous cases, there seemed to be an excess of work that was saved until the day before the deadline, which inevitably prevented us from doing the most thorough job we could, with proofreading and formatting of the report.  We learned that it would be helpful to establish a deadline for completing a draft of the report a full week before it was due, to provide us with ample time for revising it.  Furthermore, our team was assigned to potentially present on this case, meaning that we needed to factor time into the preparation process for creating a comprehensive and captivating presentation of our group strategy in this case.  Projects in the workplace may often have long term schedules, but as we have realized, beginning the process earlier, creates a less stressful atmosphere at the deadline, particularly when other pressing assignments show up with little or no warning.<br>Finally, we learned to cooperate with our partner team, Team 8, during preparation of this case.  Since one group would be presenting on behalf of both teams, it was imperative for us to share ideas with Team 8 in order to get the benefit of having eight individuals to collaborate with.  We decided that it would be best to come up with solutions to the case as two independent teams in order to generate alternative ways of choosing a strategy and then have a large Google Hangout session with all members from both teams, to see what each team had come up with.  This method would allow the two teams to critique the other’s approach and offer suggestions as constructive feedback from peers who are familiar with the information of the case.  Furthermore, having the other team’s perspective could give us new ideas about the case, which could be incorporated into our presentation and evaluated beside our initial methodology.  Having more mental capacity than any individual can provide is one important advantage of working in teams.  Therefore, having eight individuals collaborating increased the potential from </p>
<h2 id="Summary">Summary</h2>
<p>Tritec Motors’ initial lower tie bar engine block sealing design was deemed inadequate because it would not be able to keep up with the high volume production that was needed.  The design process was difficult to replicate if it was going to be done at different stations.  Without consistency in machining, quality assurance for this design would become an issue and as much as 25 percent of the cylinder blocks would need to be discarded.  This was a significant concern, which could lead to an unwanted increase in costs.<br>Two alternative designs of a rear retainer style and a bedplate design were proposed by project engineers and compared against several criteria: maximum positive impact on the 12 panel objectives (Exhibit 18), most favorable design based on factors such as sealing, design workload, assembly, and service (Exhibit 17), lowest risk with respect to design and process (Exhibits 15 and 16), and lowest amount of warranty conditions per thousand (Exhibit 14).  For the 12 panel objectives, the original tie bar design proved to be more preferable than both the bedplate and the rear retainer designs.  With respect to the factors analyzed in Exhibit 17, the bedplate design had an overall score which was higher than both alternatives.  The bedplate was the option with the lowest risk under Design Failure Mode and Effects Analysis and the second lowest risk under Process Failure Mode and Effects Analysis.  The bedplate design also finished with best warranty score, having the lowest estimated conditions per thousand.  Since the bedplate design proved to be the superior engine sealing design option in three of the five distinct categories and neither of the other two alternatives scored the highest in more than one of the categories, it was a clear decision that the bedplate design should be chosen.<br>In addition, management could be improved in this project with better communication as well as superior collaboration and support between the project staff and project manager, Jack Smith.   With management concerns addressed and risks mitigated appropriately, selection of the bedplate engine block sealing design should enable the Tritec engine joint venture to be a successful project that is capable of being completed within both time and budget constraints.</p>
<hr>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<h1 id="CHRYSLER_AND_BMW:_TRITEC_ENGINE_JOINT_VENTURE_(Section)">CHRYSLER AND BMW: TRITEC ENGINE JOINT VENTURE (Section)</h1>
<p><strong>Cre]]>
    </summary>
    
      <category term="CaseStudy" scheme="http://lianliu.me/tags/CaseStudy/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Personal Portfolio]]></title>
    <link href="http://lianliu.me/2014/11/01/20141111/"/>
    <id>http://lianliu.me/2014/11/01/20141111/</id>
    <published>2014-11-01T05:02:22.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-11-01T05:22:48.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Platform">Platform</h2>
<h3 id="Website">Website</h3>
<p><strong>Site</strong> <a href="http://www.namecheap.com" target="_blank" rel="external">Namecheap</a> student discount for one year: <a href="http://lianliu.me" target="_blank" rel="external">LianLiu.me</a><br><strong>Github</strong> <a href="http://hackerxiong.me/2014/10/12/how-to-build-a-blog-system-using-github-and-hexo/" target="_blank" rel="external">Experience</a> by XWF; <a href="https://help.github.com/articles/markdown-basics/" target="_blank" rel="external">Markdown</a> Basics; <a href="http://git-scm.com/book/zh/v1" target="_blank" rel="external">Git-book</a></p>
<h3 id="Online_Album">Online Album</h3>
<p><strong>Domestic</strong> <a href="http://weibo.com/daodao1202/profile?rightmod=1&amp;wvr=6&amp;mod=personinfo" target="_blank" rel="external">Sina</a><br><strong>International</strong> <a href="https://www.flickr.com/" target="_blank" rel="external">Flickr</a></p>
<h2 id="Works">Works</h2>
<h3 id="Business_Projects">Business Projects</h3>
<h3 id="Data_Projects">Data Projects</h3>
<h3 id="Designs_and_Media">Designs and Media</h3>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<h2 id="Platform">Platform</h2>
<h3 id="Website">Website</h3>
<p><strong>Site</strong> <a href="http://www.namecheap.com" target="_blank" re]]>
    </summary>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Hello World]]></title>
    <link href="http://lianliu.me/2014/10/31/hello-world/"/>
    <id>http://lianliu.me/2014/10/31/hello-world/</id>
    <published>2014-11-01T03:44:08.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-11-01T06:00:30.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to <a href="http://hexo.io/" target="_blank" rel="external">Hexo</a>! This is your very first post. Check <a href="http://hexo.io/docs/" target="_blank" rel="external">documentation</a> for more info. If you get any problems when using Hexo, you can find the answer in <a href="http://hexo.io/docs/troubleshooting.html" target="_blank" rel="external">trobuleshooting</a> or you can ask me on <a href="https://github.com/hexojs/hexo/issues" target="_blank" rel="external">GitHub</a>.</p>
<h2 id="Quick_Start">Quick Start</h2>
<h3 id="Create_a_new_post">Create a new post</h3>
<figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><div class="line">1</div></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><div class="line">$ hexo new <span class="string">"My New Post"</span></div></pre></td></tr></table></figure>

<p>More info: <a href="http://hexo.io/docs/writing.html" target="_blank" rel="external">Writing</a></p>
<h3 id="Run_server">Run server</h3>
<figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><div class="line">1</div></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><div class="line">$ hexo server</div></pre></td></tr></table></figure>

<p>More info: <a href="http://hexo.io/docs/server.html" target="_blank" rel="external">Server</a></p>
<h3 id="Generate_static_files">Generate static files</h3>
<figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><div class="line">1</div></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><div class="line">$ hexo generate</div></pre></td></tr></table></figure>

<p>More info: <a href="http://hexo.io/docs/generating.html" target="_blank" rel="external">Generating</a></p>
<h3 id="Deploy_to_remote_sites">Deploy to remote sites</h3>
<figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><div class="line">1</div></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><div class="line">$ hexo deploy</div></pre></td></tr></table></figure>

<p>More info: <a href="http://hexo.io/docs/deployment.html" target="_blank" rel="external">Deployment</a></p>
<p>add ssh to github<br>config email and name<br>hexo generate<br>hexo deploy</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>Welcome to <a href="http://hexo.io/" target="_blank" rel="external">Hexo</a>! This is your very first post. Check <a href="http://hexo.io]]>
    </summary>
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
