<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title><![CDATA[Lian Liu]]></title>
  <subtitle><![CDATA[Learn more about me]]></subtitle>
  <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://lianliu.me/"/>
  <updated>2015-07-23T04:28:15.085Z</updated>
  <id>http://lianliu.me/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Lian.Liu]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[durianl1988@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="http://zespia.tw/hexo/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[北方游记（四）]]></title>
    <link href="http://lianliu.me/2015/07/23/%E5%8C%97%E6%96%B9%E6%B8%B8%E8%AE%B0%EF%BC%88%E5%9B%9B%EF%BC%89/"/>
    <id>http://lianliu.me/2015/07/23/北方游记（四）/</id>
    <published>2015-07-23T04:22:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-07-23T04:27:18.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>从奥斯陆起飞、经停挪威北部城市Tromso出关，历时四小时，抵达北纬七十八度的Longyearbyen（Svalbard群岛首府）。当从机舱向外能够眺望到被积雪覆盖的一望无际的山脉时，你就知道，你已迈入北极圈。<br><img src="http://fmn.rrimg.com/fmn061/20120818/0140/b_large_njvJ_670a0000974c1263.jpg" alt=""></p>
<p>朗伊尔机场临海而建，距离市区仅十分钟车程（或许是世界上离市区最近的机场了吧？），夏季每周有十四个班次来往挪威首都奥斯陆；冬季则减少为五次。距机场车程十分钟即到达狭长山谷中的小镇中心——设有邮局、餐厅、诊所、超市、博物馆、大学和极地研究所。常住人口约2000人，但也不都是永久居民。<br>除了挪威人，泰国人是这里的第二大族群——几十年前一位这里的科学家去泰国度假，娶回了一位泰国媳妇；姑娘来后发现这里生活安稳赚钱机会也多，就从家乡带了许多姐妹朋友，渐渐发展壮大。由于大叔坚持要吃中餐。。。我们只好退而求其次吃了泰国菜。。。事实证明还是不错的=,=<br><img src="http://fmn.rrimg.com/fmn061/20120818/0150/b_large_ESR4_69b800000dee1261.jpg" alt=""><br>死亡，在这里是绝对禁止的——生病了，政府会派飞机接你回挪威大陆治疗、若是因意外暴毙，也不允许葬在岛上。因为极地的冻土地带，尸体在这里是不会腐烂的——这也引起了一些奇怪癖好的人来研究这一现象。</p>
<p>同样是因为极寒，Longyearbyen还有传说中的“末日种子库”，也就是世界种子库，建在机场附近的山坡上。基地建设由挪威农业部出资，但贮藏其中的种子归贡献国所有。可惜由于整个基地只有一个出入口，非常不利于逃生，现已被消防部门禁止游客参观了（图中半山腰那个灰色建筑物）。<br><img src="http://fmn.rrimg.com/fmn057/20120818/0200/b_large_CX0p_70d900007f301262.jpg" alt=""><br>尽管人口聚集区没有发现过北极熊，但少偏僻的地方确实有发现北极熊的报告。所以在这里是不建议独自一人离开聚居地过远的；远足或登山等需要带上武器（枪或者长刀）。这段时间岛上正爆发狂犬病，从Tromso出关时机场就反复提示，不可太靠近野生动物、遇到可疑情况及时上报等。<br><img src="http://fmn.rrfmn.com/fmn058/20120818/0210/b_large_VvZ8_39c500006b971262.jpg" alt=""><br>在Longyearbyen，另一项特别的习俗是室内必须脱鞋——穿袜子或者室内拖鞋；公共场合门口都有敞开式的公共鞋柜。我估摸着是因为这里劳动力稀缺没有足够的人手来打扫卫生。好在尽管刚从气候宜人的奥斯陆来到这个室外寒风刀割的地方，室内仍旧温暖入春，当地人往往衬衫甚至短袖与裹得笨拙的游客形成鲜明对比。</p>
<p>Svalbard群岛由挪威代管，受“Svalbard Treaty”的约束，包括：岛上适用挪威宪法、保护环境为第一守则、签署条约的各国享有平等但并非无限的权利等。由于它的特殊地位，各国来这里不需要签证（可惜没有直接从国内飞这里的航班）、岛上所有商品也都免税（木有奢侈品，烟酒化妆品之类的）。所有食物来自大陆进口、饮用水来自岛上的淡水湖泊——经过复杂的净化工艺以除去大量的矿物颗粒——这是个矿产丰富的群岛。<br>岛上的主要资源是煤矿，为发电厂提供能源；也有少量金矿和放射性元素钯，但遵从于“保护环境为第一守则”，这些矿藏目前并不允许开采。<br>在极地研究所，可以看到这里的工作人员为环境监测、保护和预警做出了长期、艰苦而卓越的贡献。与南极洲被海水包围的大陆恰好相反，北冰洋则是一片被大陆包围的海洋、更多地受到洋流和大陆风的影响。在温室效应和洋流的双重影响下，北冰洋的平均冰层面积在二十年里减少了将近二分之一。气温的升高也相当显著。</p>
<p>在八十年代，格林兰岛和加拿大附近的北冰洋区域存在大量五年冰龄以上的浮冰，厚度达到6米以上；而现在，大部分都是当年冰（即冬天存在、夏天融化），两米以上的冰已经很难发现了。就拿极地研究所附近的峡湾为例，今年冬季由于海水过暖，尽管陆地温度降至零下四十度左右，但整个峡湾都没有结冰——与往年形成鲜明对比。<br>朗伊尔城只有夏季和冬季。在黑夜漫漫的冬季，是这里的social season，大家挨家串门、聊天聚会。夏季则热闹不少——除非遇上极地风暴，可能几周就会出现一次，但持续时间也就五六个小时左右。<br>来到这里，才深刻意识到“保护环境”绝非一句口号而已。上升的海平面、融化的冰层正在切实威胁着这里的生命——海鸟捉不到鱼可能会饿死、北极熊游不到岸可能会淹死；能够为它们做的，我会多做一点。</p>
<p>后话：有时候想想很矛盾——如此脆弱的生态系统，随着越来越多的游客、科研人员的到来必将对其造成难以弥补的损伤；但正是因为有人来了看了，才能亲历这片土地的神圣和伟大、于是从心底里知道要如何爱它；科研的作用不仅是在帮助维持这里的生态，更为整个地球的环境变化提供实体借鉴和理论依据。由此，觉得QuarkExpeditions在我们的整个航程中真心给予了专业、尽职的指导和教育，让我们不仅饱览了极地的壮美风光，更自觉努力把对这里的影响降到最小；同时，还赚饱了一肚子的极地动植物历史地理知识！以上这些我在之后几天会陆续po上来和大家分享。但在之后的某一天，希望你也能亲自来这里看一看！</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>从奥斯陆起飞、经停挪威北部城市Tromso出关，历时四小时，抵达北纬七十八度的Longyearbyen（Svalbard群岛首府）。当从机舱向外能够眺望到被积雪覆盖的一望无际的山脉时，你就知道，你已迈入北极圈。<br><img src="http://fmn.rrimg.c]]>
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Travel" scheme="http://lianliu.me/tags/Travel/"/>
    
      <category term="Writing" scheme="http://lianliu.me/tags/Writing/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[北方游记（三）]]></title>
    <link href="http://lianliu.me/2015/07/23/%E5%8C%97%E6%96%B9%E6%B8%B8%E8%AE%B0%EF%BC%88%E4%B8%89%EF%BC%89/"/>
    <id>http://lianliu.me/2015/07/23/北方游记（三）/</id>
    <published>2015-07-23T04:17:20.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-07-23T04:21:31.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>我们在奥斯陆的导游是个十来岁就和父母来挪威的上海小姑娘，如今已经当妈了。虽然中文讲得已经稍有生疏，但和老公打电话的时候还是流利地开起上海话，对于来了这边就没有回过国的人来说也算不易了。在车上聊得很开心，对奥斯陆和挪威有了多一些了解。<br>由于人口基数小、生育率也不高，导致挪威劳动力稀缺、价格昂贵，所以工业基本消失（空气真心好啊！）。93年投票的时候有52%反对加入欧盟，所以现在也没进去，使用的也是挪威克朗，比人民币稍微贵一点。<br>为了感谢英国在二战期间对挪威的支持，挪威每年都会从国内挑选一棵圣诞树送给英国，也算是两国友谊的长久见证。<br>挪威的幼儿园收费是根据父母收入来定的，小学为七年制，整个小学期间都没有考试；小学毕业后就近进入初中，三年间的所有平时考试成绩决定了可以申请的高中级别。考试为6分制，5分以上就可以进入比较好的高中了；在初中期间辅修一门二外（英语为必修）可以加分，学得比较多的是西班牙语，选法语的比较少，德语因为和挪威语比较像，选的也比较多；进了高中还可以选意大利语、中文或者日语韩语，这样考大学又可以加分了。在挪威如果想做医生或者律师，必须要6分哦。<br>挪威是世界有名的“从摇篮到坟墓”的福利全覆盖国家。比如说生宝宝自然是全免费的，上学不需要学费、教科书是学校循环使用的，学校提供一顿午餐（只是沿袭着海盗的传统供应冷餐）、去年开始小朋友们在学校还可以免费吃水果。看病免费，但整个奥斯陆只有两个医院（第三个最近关掉了），所以大医院常年人满为患排队极长，只有生孩子这种十万火急的事儿才可以随到随办。但是每个人都有保健医生和专科医生来应付各种小毛小病，出了大问题才用去医院排队。<br>医生在挪威真心是个好职业，拿下自然也非易事，经过6年学习和6年实习，当上医生要30+了。退休年龄男女一样，67岁，一些特种职业要求高一点，比如警察、消防员、飞行员都是60岁。同样是因为劳动力稀缺，去年的新政策是67岁之后老人们可以继续工作，不扣养老金。事实是，在挪威，70岁的老人仍旧精力充沛，一般工作完全可以继续胜任。这也导致了大学毕业的年轻人很难找工作，失业率高达4%；失业率更高的瑞典还要雪上加霜——年轻人都跑挪威打工了。。。<br>至于休假，那可正是被我们赶上了。和我之前想象的不一样，这边在极夜的时候大家是起早贪黑地工作的；等到夏天来了，就会充分利用一个多月的休假开上房车一路游玩——反正挪威峡湾多得是，camp site和房车基地也非常普及；休假期间的工资由政府支付。但是玩归玩，家里的事情还是要自己做——这里的劳动力实在太贵了，修房顶、换雪胎、打扫院子，学校甚至还会专门开设家政课，教授织毛衣缝纫之类的课程。<br>在挪威，公会力量不可小觑，带领员工胁迫公司加薪是常事儿，一年要涨1-2%的工资，两年左右来一次大罢工，今年的谈判使平均税前工资增长了4%。<br>由于历史上漫长的海盗时期，挪威人还是比较看重“入土为安”的。反正地广人稀，公墓就建在市里像个小公园似的，没什么风水的讲究。</p>
<p>今天在挪威除了一些私事儿，还去了奥斯陆必到景点Vigelang雕塑公园——艺术家用毕生的精力完成了园内的所有雕塑的设计，所有雕塑都是裸体——受古希腊时期艺术风格影响，皆以人体为美。建设期间由于二战被暂停了五年；Vigelang并没能等到1943年公园的落成。<br>公园分生命之桥、生命之树和生命之柱三个板块，顺便说一句，谷歌街景可以清晰看到全貌哦！150m长的生命之桥两边的58尊雕塑展示了人的一生从出生到死亡的每个阶段。<br><img src="http://fmn.rrimg.com/fmn059/20120816/2335/b_large_6OKH_3d610000542a1261.jpg" alt=""><br>最有名的angry boy，在奥斯陆机场都有他的照片，每个经过的游客都喜欢拉着他的小手合影，所以青铜雕塑的左手已经金光灿灿了。</p>
<p>桥下有座“娃娃园”，正中间是一个大头朝下蜷缩的小孩，稍微有点生理知识就知道是还在妈妈肚子里咯！周围一圈围着各种姿态的小孩，凳子都是小朋友的尺寸，周末当地父母都会带小朋友来这里亲近大自然。<br><img src="http://fmn.rrimg.com/fmn061/20120816/2355/b_large_H9bh_70d9000046931262.jpg" alt=""><br>生命之树是四组五人雕像，分别代表人的一生的童年、青年、壮年和老年。每组的人都交错盘叠在一起，形成树的姿态。四组雕塑环绕一周，象征生命的轮回。</p>
<p>最后的生命之柱由121人互相纠缠组成，高17米，花岗岩雕刻。站在旁边可以俯视公园全景——完美轴对称的布局，从入口一路向前走到这里，看完全部内容没有重复，就可以从后门出去了。挪威的天气真是瞬息万变，晴空万里到倾盆大雨只用了三十秒，五分钟以后又是好天气了。。。</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>我们在奥斯陆的导游是个十来岁就和父母来挪威的上海小姑娘，如今已经当妈了。虽然中文讲得已经稍有生疏，但和老公打电话的时候还是流利地开起上海话，对于来了这边就没有回过国的人来说也算不易了。在车上聊得很开心，对奥斯陆和挪威有了多一些了解。<br>由于人口基数小、生育率也不高，导致]]>
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Travel" scheme="http://lianliu.me/tags/Travel/"/>
    
      <category term="Writing" scheme="http://lianliu.me/tags/Writing/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[北方游记（二）]]></title>
    <link href="http://lianliu.me/2015/07/23/%E5%8C%97%E6%96%B9%E6%B8%B8%E8%AE%B0%EF%BC%88%E4%BA%8C%EF%BC%89/"/>
    <id>http://lianliu.me/2015/07/23/北方游记（二）/</id>
    <published>2015-07-23T04:09:01.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-07-23T04:17:06.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>北欧关于吸烟的政策是见天吸烟，违者重罚。</p>
<p>瑞典的公共交通：一般可以购买200克朗的八次卡，上面有16个小方块。一次区内公交车用两格、一次区内地铁三格，跨多一区再加多一格；一小时内转乘不再扣费。如果觉得贵得很，还是要提醒你一下他们人均25000-28000的收入。不过出租车倒是贵得惊人，起步费40克朗——货真价实的起步费哦——车一启动，计价器就从40开始狂跳，市区10min的路程多要一百以上，心脏不好的人千万不能乘。所以在瑞典也很少有人打车，大多都有私家车；油费也不贵，一般的95#汽油15克朗/升。打车人少，马路上自然看不到出租车跑来跑去，一般都是电话订车居多。由于计价器实在跳得太快，从机场到城区就实施了固定收费：460克朗可以到市中心任何地方；根据车型不同会略有调整。</p>
<p>从峡湾街——市区的最高点（其实也就是个百米小丘），可以俯瞰斯德哥尔摩市全景。Stockholm的名字由stock木头和holm岛组成——以前为了抵御海盗入侵，国王带领大家沿海竖起木桩，远远望去就像木头做的岛屿。 </p>
<p>在这里历史上曾经发生过三位领导人遇刺。最近的一次是安娜林德。由于主张加入欧元区，那个开钱庄的年轻人认为因此将利益受损，在跟踪了许多天后在红色的北欧百货大楼试衣间将她杀害，此后再没人敢提加入欧元区。。。瑞典没有死刑，这家伙被判了终生监禁。 </p>
<p><img src="http://fmn.rrimg.com/fmn057/20120816/0020/b_large_qznp_19bb000052bb1261.jpg" alt=""><br>上图是市区的格兰酒店，斯德哥尔摩最豪华、历史最悠久的酒店之一。每年它都为诺贝尔奖获得者提供一晚免费住宿。此外，他也接待了无数外国政要，包括中国的敏感词和敏感词。</p>
<p> 瑞典的名气，很大一部分来自于诺贝尔奖。当年诺贝尔先生设立此奖时，国王希望是一个瑞典国家范围内的奖项，而诺贝尔却搞大了，搞成了世界奖项。所以第一年颁奖，国王气得没有出席；第二年来了五分钟，觉得不错；第三年之后，便每届都从头到尾参加了。</p>
<p><img src="http://fmn.rrimg.com/fmn064/20120816/0020/b_large_vT8L_4bdb00001bfa1262.jpg" alt=""><br>举行晚宴的市政厅落成于1923年。之前市政会议多借国会大厦，由于位子紧张常常借不到，斯德哥尔摩市一赌气就自己建了一座更好的建筑。由于建立在老城区，为了与周围的旧房子和谐一致，外墙红砖都细心做了磨旧处理。 </p>
<p>建筑物顶部有三座高低有别的皇冠，分别象征北欧三国中地位最高的瑞典、次高的丹麦和最低的挪威，因为挪威被丹麦和瑞典都统治过。。。 </p>
<p>现任国王拥有“盖章权”，继任者将是他的女儿——当年还是腹中胎儿时，第一次当爹的国王就兴奋地宣布无论是男是女，都将立其为王。</p>
<p>诺贝尔奖中，经济学奖是后来增加了——可能是为了弥补空白的数学奖吧！诺贝尔先生曾立下遗嘱永远不能把数学奖加进来。因为他的女朋友，就是在一次舞会上被数学家抢走的，何况他本来也认为和数字打交道是一门甚为无用的学问。这些奖项中，和平奖被单放在挪威颁发，是因为当时挪威一直受瑞典资助，瑞典希望它能尽快够独立起来。</p>
<p>大厅的台阶格外平缓，因为参加晚宴的女士多着华丽的长摆晚礼服，从台阶上缓缓走下——平缓的台阶恰能展现她们优雅的步态，极宽的阶面可以防止裙摆被踩到。</p>
<p>市政会议的设备每两周都会有专人维护，确保市政会议时每位议员的意见都能够充分表达。</p>
<p>任何人都可以在旁听席坐下来——限额160人；外国人也可以，只是他们是讲瑞典语的。顺便说一句，瑞典语的小舌音极重，据说很多瑞典孩子都发不好这个音，于是还有专门教授这种发音的学校=,=.<br><img src="http://fmn.rrimg.com/fmn064/20120816/0020/b_large_OhiC_2522000008751263.jpg" alt=""><br>大厅上方类似星空，寓意“我们谈话的内容公开透明，人人都可以听到”</p>
<p>设计精巧的水晶灯——虽然水晶是瑞典的一大特色，可是建造时为了节约成本，仍然采用了这种精巧的设计，现在这种思路也广泛应用在之后的各种装潢案例中。</p>
<p>著名的金色大厅，壁画皆由金色马赛克镶拼。<br><img src="http://fmn.rrimg.com/fmn056/20120816/0025/b_large_ZQmu_3d6100001d981261.jpg" alt=""><br>可惜展示的是一位粗心艺术家的壁画，要说里面出现的错误，那还真是数不胜数。最不可饶恕的应该是“无头国王”吧——设计计算的时候，艺术家忽略了墙角线的高度，然后。。。画到上面画不下了=,=<br><img src="http://fmn.rrimg.com/fmn062/20120816/0025/b_large_aE3Q_7be40000649e1262.jpg" alt=""><br>国王倒是相当大度，说：你们只要把我放在心里就可以了，没有取其性命。此外还能看到本来应该是三座王冠的北欧象征居然只画了两座（这得有多粗心）。然后么，就是水神梅兰女神，画得其丑无比。居然还解释得头头是道——大眼睛用来辨识坏人、粗壮的手臂担负起国家重担、巨大的脚板能够稳稳地守住江山、水怪一样的长发其实是波浪的化身。。。 </p>
<p>诺贝尔晚宴虽然鼎鼎大名，其实却只有四道菜：龙虾、三文鱼、鹿肉和诺贝尔冰激凌。所以当年法国华裔作家高行健获得诺贝尔文学奖时，就抱怨喋喋没吃饱，回了旅店再煮泡面吃。喝的东西倒是很多啦：鸡尾酒、葡萄酒、餐后甜酒、白兰地、威士忌。。。</p>
<p>中午12点左右，在瑞典皇宫广场举行表演般的皇家卫兵换岗仪式，整个广场陆陆续续被里三层外三层围得水泄不通，看来这种仪式早就成了瑞典旅游的重要组成部分。</p>
<p>和想象中的士兵很不同，这些人都白白胖胖的，谈不上花瓶，却也不威严。天气极好，士兵的蓝衣服和无云的明媚天色如出一辙；温度20℃左右，游客短袖凉鞋齐出动，他们长袖长裤的制服加皮手套大帽子，任由成为摆拍的工具也纹丝不动。<br><img src="http://fmn.rrimg.com/fmn059/20120816/0030/b_large_PmXs_417a00001bc91261.jpg" alt=""><br>军乐队首先浩浩荡荡地出场，国歌声毕上岗和下岗士兵开始进行一系列表演式的复杂动作以完成交接班；军乐一刻不停，乐队还在行进中不断变换队形， 玩得花样百出。北欧果然是高度重视男女平等的国家，乐队中不乏女性乐手，还有几位四眼人士。换岗结束后乐队又行进到教堂前的广场开始了更为亲民的演奏，小朋友们蹒跚穿梭在乐队里、姑娘们贴着鼓手亲密合影，真是一派和谐盛世。</p>
<p>其他一些关于瑞典的信息：四年加一年考察期拿绿卡、七年国籍，也就是拿选票之类的（话说瑞典语这么难学，七年也不一定讲得顺溜=,=）。</p>
<p>每年十月至次年五月的冬季必须换雪胎开车。两三天不开车，积雪轻松就能没过车顶。</p>
<p>由于地广人稀劳动力昂贵，农业普遍机械化，大部分种植小麦和草皮。为了保护地下水，农药时绝对禁止的。蔬菜主要从德国、荷兰进口，青菜70克朗一公斤、韭菜几乎都是论根卖的。自产的水果包括夏季的草莓、樱桃和野山莓。</p>
<p>快到机场的时候路边可以看到一架破旧的飞机——由退役飞机改装而成的胶囊旅馆，专供转机旅客过夜。虽然创意不错，生意却非常一般，现在已经打算转手卖掉了。</p>
<p> 斯德哥尔摩-奥斯陆</p>
<p>奥斯陆和斯德哥尔摩相比，山地气候相当明显，早晚冷、中午热，小范围、短时的降雨说来就来；空气清新得令人发指。和瑞典一样，夏季也是这里的度假季，上周的30℃已被媒体惊呼为“历史高温”。夏季收获草莓和苹果，但气候导致苹果的口味实在不好，自家小范围的果树多；60万人口中25%为移民（包括父母至少有一方不出生在挪威的二代移民）。Oslo意味“水边的地”，海岸线长达100公里。</p>
<p>在1969年发现石油之前，挪威并不富裕。即使是发现了储量丰富的北海油田，也主要由英国人帮忙开采。挪威每个人有约30万的石油基金，但不同政党对于这笔基金的使用与否存在不同意见，至今还未直接使用过。</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>北欧关于吸烟的政策是见天吸烟，违者重罚。</p>
<p>瑞典的公共交通：一般可以购买200克朗的八次卡，上面有16个小方块。一次区内公交车用两格、一次区内地铁三格，跨多一区再加多一格；一小时内转乘不再扣费。如果觉得贵得很，还是要提醒你一下他们人均25000-28000的收入]]>
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Travel" scheme="http://lianliu.me/tags/Travel/"/>
    
      <category term="Writing" scheme="http://lianliu.me/tags/Writing/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[北方游记（一）]]></title>
    <link href="http://lianliu.me/2015/07/23/%E5%8C%97%E6%96%B9%E6%B8%B8%E8%AE%B0%EF%BC%88%E4%B8%80%EF%BC%89/"/>
    <id>http://lianliu.me/2015/07/23/北方游记（一）/</id>
    <published>2015-07-23T04:02:09.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-07-23T04:16:37.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>更新一些前几年出去玩写的旧文，督促自己去哪里玩都要继续写东西。文字部分倒还好，只是当年的拍照水平真心不忍直视，感觉辜负了北欧的明媚和北极的冷峻。还好留在了心里。</p>
<p>出发这天上海天气特别好，起飞的时候城市全貌一览无余，毫不费力地就辨别出了黄浦江、东方明珠、体育馆、虹桥机场（我们从浦东飞的）。<br>原本想象难熬的九个小时航行，在看了四部电影后不知不觉就到了，除了屏幕差劲得要死、耳机只有一只有声音外，一切都好。今天一共吃了五顿饭，如果国航淡而无味的蛋炒饭和臭烘烘的鸡肉饭也算饭的话。。。总之顺利抵达斯德哥尔摩，看到北欧的蓝天心情激动得无以复加。</p>
<p>瑞典人应该是对自己的祖国颇为引以为豪吧，机场大多数设施只标注瑞典语，广播也好像没有英文；或者是口音太重完全没有听出来。好在看拼写能够大致猜出什么意思。行李提取处的墙上贴满welcome to my home town的宣传画，上镜的大多是平凡的瑞典人，当然也有演艺明星、大公司CEO，以及国王和王后。总之，让你瞬间对这个国家和城市有了亲切感。</p>
<p>我们来的时候，这里刚过一天有22小时日照的仲夏节，但白天依旧长到晚上八点仍可见蓝天白云。冬天则恰好相反，商店也多在晚上六点就打烊了——却不熄灯——整个城市打造出不夜城的景象。</p>
<p>同样不熄灯的还有街头的汽车：这里的汽车从点火开始，前灯就是亮着的，只能调节亮度、不能控制开闭。也是因为这里半年都是极夜的缘故。<br>飞机降落前往下看，就可以知道瑞典何来森林王国的美誉。树种大多为落叶的白桦和常绿的杉木。大片绿草中散落着半人高的白色包裹，据说是为牲畜冬天储备的草料。</p>
<p>整个斯德哥尔摩约有150万人口，市区80万左右，但是每逢阳光充沛的6-8月，他们便举家度假——一部房车浩浩荡荡地开往海滩、湖边。瑞典的车后面都配有挂钩，如果不想租房车，也可以拖一个在后面的；车顶的行李架用来携带自行车或滑雪板。<br>高速限速110-120km，收费站只在工作日的白天收费，且根据时间段调整价格——这也是为了缓解进入市区的交通压力，在工作日，堵车同样困扰着这个城市。公交专用道仅供公交车和出租车行驶，同时大家都非常自觉遵守这项规定。<br>瑞典是公认的四高国家：高收入、高税收、高福利、高消费。人均收入能达到25000-28000（瑞典克朗），但其中约30%用来交税。由此带来的高福利包括失业保险、残疾人福利、生产福利等等。由于高度重视平等，在这里男人也是需要休产假抚养宝宝的。夫妻双方总共可以休一年半的产假，之后宝宝就可以送进托儿所了。<br>瑞典临海临湖，隔开波罗的海和Malaren湖水的桥下有座闸门。因为湖水来自雪山融化的积雪，当水位升高时，闸门就会打开使湖水入海，而海水不会倒灌。这样一来，湖水仍是淡水，但海水却越来越淡。加之整个波罗的海参与洋流少，淡水不易排出，所以在这一带的海鲜并不多，味道也不够鲜美。<br>从斯德哥尔摩开车前往挪威约500公里，其中400公里开至两国边境。每天有船往返芬兰的两个城市——图库和首都赫尔辛基。<br>小心钱包！欧盟开放过快也恶化了这里的治安。<br>多出了六个小时，却也只能早早睡觉——北欧之行正式开始，为了玩得开心要赶紧养精蓄锐！<br>明天内容：斯德哥尔摩市政厅、皇家卫兵换岗；晚上飞奥斯陆——我最爱的挪威(≧▽≦)</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>更新一些前几年出去玩写的旧文，督促自己去哪里玩都要继续写东西。文字部分倒还好，只是当年的拍照水平真心不忍直视，感觉辜负了北欧的明媚和北极的冷峻。还好留在了心里。</p>
<p>出发这天上海天气特别好，起飞的时候城市全貌一览无余，毫不费力地就辨别出了黄浦江、东方明珠、体育馆、]]>
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Travel" scheme="http://lianliu.me/tags/Travel/"/>
    
      <category term="Writing" scheme="http://lianliu.me/tags/Writing/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[一墙之隔]]></title>
    <link href="http://lianliu.me/2015/07/09/%E4%B8%80%E5%A2%99%E4%B9%8B%E9%9A%94/"/>
    <id>http://lianliu.me/2015/07/09/一墙之隔/</id>
    <published>2015-07-09T02:47:52.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-07-09T12:51:25.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>连上了学校的vpn，我的dropbox文件夹终于可以颤颤巍巍地同步了。<br>有时候觉得自己也是no zuo no die——明明国内其他小伙伴在网上也过得好好的，留学回来的也不过是偶尔抱怨下facebook上不去然后手机上装个vpn也就搞定了，为什么我每次一想起上网就满满的幽怨……<br>首先我原本引以为傲的“云端办公”都变成单机版了——我在dropbox有一个和本地同步的文件夹，专门存档当前频繁使用的文件。比如说申请工作期间的简历、cover letter和申请进度汇总表；旅行期间的各种凭证扫描件、攻略、自制的行程单。这样我就可以随时在手机上查看或者做一些简单的更新；自己电脑不在身边的时候也可以从网站下载下来编辑。<br>平时喜欢拍照，即使不出游也举着相机快门乱按。都说拍照片要懂得取舍——专业摄影师都这样。于是g+的自动备份功能对于选择困难症患者来说简直是天降甘霖——每次从SD卡把照片拷出来，g+就自动备份到云端；然后我再挑出满意的精修，剩下的删光！毕竟笔记本那点儿空间……更让我喜欢的功能是，手机可以随时访问自己的google主页挑照片，随手就po到各种社交网站了。iPhone的摄像头再好，哪里比得过单反的300dpi？<br>我们很多课程都需要用到雪片纷飞的case book. 所以开会讨论、做作业时常常用电子版——笔记本大小的iPad，装满了整个学期所有课程的教材，做笔记时的圈圈画画全都用google drive或者dropbox的账号同步起来，到哪里打开来都一样。不过现在也没有case要看啦，这里影响稍微小一点。</p>
<p>好了，你说我no zuo no die我也认了——“你可以用百度云管家代替dropbox啊”“国内很多网盘用起来也很方便啊”……谁让你信不过无处不在的大百度？谁让你看不上国内软件偏要用墙外同步的Notability和Day One? Chrome的搜索栏报废了？不喜欢百度你也可以换成Bing嘛！那些歇菜的chrome插件，用火狐替代啊！什么？Any.do也不能同步了？国内也有很多待办事项的app你没必要吊死在一棵树上嘛！Pushbullet好棒啊！文字、图片、链接、地址，想发到哪儿就发到哪儿，太适合我这种移动设备过多的人使用了，暂时也没有合适的替代……</p>
<p>这些我都忍了，我可以用我信得过的替代品（百度呵呵），或者我自己翻出去就好，但是总不能强迫别人也和我一块儿翻吧？虽然工作和生活中的文件分享、合作编辑的情况不至于像读书时那么频繁——每门课都有Team, 经常都是在Google Drive建一个文件夹，各自做好了往里面丢；甚至六个人坐在一间房里开会，每个人都对着电脑在线上一起编辑同一个文档——但遇到分享大文件、多人会议之类的情况，我还是感到非常无助。好了啦，不要作啦，就用一下QQ好啦！</p>
<p>作为“天生爱吐槽”的我，也忍不住吐槽自己明明才出去一年，为什么变得如此“崇洋媚外”。可是我记得我出去之前国内的网络环境好像也没有恶化到这种地步啊——Google不能用，但邮件还是可以收的；dropbox和Instagram也是可以用的；你知道当我听说g+可以免费无限制存储高精度图片的时候（之前我都是压缩上传的啊啊啊啊）已经身在国内的我有多忧桑嘛？难道google就真的那么好嘛？哈哈哈我就是好愿意把我的一切都上传到云端分享给google，让它了解我分析我，进而推荐适合我的广告、推送我需要的通知、在合适的时候周到地提醒我待办事宜。我能够认识到线上共享的隐患，能够遇见个人信息泄露可能造成的影响，但我坚信云端共享是互联网的未来，大数据此刻可能过热却是信息时代发展的必然。不仅是因为数据挖掘、趋势研究已经逐渐被证明它们存在的价值，也因为互联网的普及、可穿戴设备的渗入正在以生产技术难以匹敌的速度创造着大量数据，本地存储必将被淘汰！所以即使有隐患，我还是愿意走在前面，并且选择我更信得过的服务。</p>
<p>啊，扯远了……本来只是吐槽越来越高越管越宽的墙，为什么境界莫名升华了呢……我就是立个贴，要好好把家里的网络环境改造好（嗯，任重而道不远），将来有了小孩，要让他成长在没有墙的环境里！想想我从没多少国外好友的时期就开始用facebook了，就是坚信有一天我们终能像别人一样自由地上网，也是很心酸的……</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>连上了学校的vpn，我的dropbox文件夹终于可以颤颤巍巍地同步了。<br>有时候觉得自己也是no zuo no die——明明国内其他小伙伴在网上也过得好好的，留学回来的也不过是偶尔抱怨下facebook上不去然后手机上装个vpn也就搞定了，为什么我每次一想起上网就满满]]>
    </summary>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[MEM Hooding Ceremony Speech]]></title>
    <link href="http://lianliu.me/2015/05/17/MEM-Hooding-Ceremony-Speech/"/>
    <id>http://lianliu.me/2015/05/17/MEM-Hooding-Ceremony-Speech/</id>
    <published>2015-05-17T11:07:54.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-06-08T04:48:58.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Was designated to be the MEM Hooding Ceremony speaker of my classmates at Duke University. Special Thanks to <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/stacithornton" target="_blank" rel="external">Staci Thornton</a> and <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/alecweisman" target="_blank" rel="external">Alec Weisman</a> for the suggestions and proofreading.<br><a href="https://youtu.be/dgzRpy86zrc?t=9m44s" target="_blank" rel="external">Speech Video</a><br><img src="http://ww1.sinaimg.cn/mw690/72a818edjw1es0j78idfbj20qo0hsgnv.jpg" alt=""><br>Good afternoon. Distinguished guests, faculty and staff, family and friends, thank you for coming today, to show your support for us and our achievements! Congratulations, my dear classmates! It’s an honor to be standing up here to review the past and look forward. Thank you for giving me this opportunity…..I am sure you won’t regret it.<br>What makes MEM special, the <a href="http://memp.pratt.duke.edu/" target="_blank" rel="external">Master of Engineering Management</a> program? I invite you to look back at the year together with me. Yes, please join me! (the following section involves some interactions with the audience) Who said “if I don’t see you at seminars, you are gonna see me.”? (Dr. Murray). Yes, we have the most conscientious and generous staff and faculty. Thank you, Dr. Glass, Dr. Fox, Dr. Murray, for bringing us an insightful, challenging and enjoyable program. Who has been married for 13,314 days till today? (CJ Skender) Yes, we have the most experienced and charming professors. Thank you, to all of the professors…for providing us with a vivid perspective of the industry.  Your dedication to teaching doesn’t stop in the classroom, but continues through lunches and coffee hours. Do you still remember our very first Guide to Durham, with all the interesting places to eat, to do and to buy? (Bridget) And who always brought dogs to MEM suite during the intense final weeks? (Lorelle) yes, we have an amazing and trustworthy staff. Thank you, Staci, Susan, Erin, Jamila, Bridget, and Lorelle, for making us feel like a part of this big family, and a part of a winning team. Who has read every version of our resumes and cover letters? (Jenny, etc.) Yes, we have the most reliable career service team. Thank you, Jenny, Leah, Christina, for being available, helpful and encouraging all the time on our career path.<br>Friday afternoon is our favorite time at MEM. Not only because of the food from all around the world, which is important, but also because of the insightful seminars and splendid cultural presentations. Not only do we have the opportunity to gain close connections with industry experts, but also to learn cultural diversity from each other. The rest of the week is delightful as well. We spent three months running a medicine company; went ecstatic or crazy with the up and down of the stock price. We successfully led a chaotic team to complete the project in time even though our poor boss Ana left the company with 200 failed projects. We helped Ella and Tomas deal with all the legal issues when they launched their love bubble company. The courses were sometimes frustrating; the deadlines were always one after another, but in the end they made us feel accomplished.<br>Looking forward, I’d like to share with you three things about choice, which I learned from MEM, and will be invaluable for the future.<br>Staci always says, I can do nothing if you find me after the course add and drop ends. The choice of courses determines our sleep quality, happiness index, and—to some extent—our final grades. It is important but we only have two weeks to make the choice. If you miss the deadline, not even Staci can help you. So seize the day and make your choice! Opportunities are passing by never to return. If you meet someone friendly and charming, don’t hesitate; go and talk to him, or her. Because they will leave and you may not see them again. that is an advice for attending career fairs. We are afforded many opportunities in life… take advantage and make the choices in time.<br>The second thing I want to leave us today is that there is no need to regret the choices you have made. In our  first seminar, Jason McMain said “to plan is worthwhile but the plan itself is worthless”. This is the fascination of our time. Things change so quickly that we can no longer predict what will happen next. A bad choice now may turn into an opportunity later. Glancing down and regretting on the past will only blind you from what lies ahead. Just like sitting in class, drifting away for only two minutes, you will feel completely lost about the concept. But if you then try to go back and start again, you will miss the whole class and will need more than three hours to make up what you missed. What if we really make some bad choices? In the PharmaSim Simulation, we probably all make some…questionable decisions, reducing the price, killing a product, spending money on meaningless tests. Instead of blaming each other or regretting it, we always analyzed and reported the data in order to find better solutions. We need to convert bad choices into opportunities.<br>Last but not the least, your choices deserve respect; so do others. One of the most distinguishing aspects of the MEM program is that we learn from engineers with background in all kinds of industries and cultures. We argued fiercely in class discussion. We had tears in team projects. But agreeing to disagree is the catalyst of progress. Outside the classroom, we have been able to collect on the dividends of diversity. Our classmates invited us to parties for Diwali; we had mooncakes for the Mid-autumn Festival. We celebrated New Year’s Day together; learned French, Russian and Spanish. We explain to each other the meanings of our names. This experience with you has taught me to embrace our differences. So, even when I cannot understand the choices made by others, I learn to respect it.<br>Life is a one-way journey. Our choices enlighten the way. Some choices lead us to spectacular scenery; some bring us barriers and ambiguities. But we never know what will happen next. What we can do is to learn from experience and make better choices. MEM has equipped us with the appreciation of sceneries, the knowledge to turn barriers into opportunities and the courage to face ambiguities. While our beautiful, wonderful, magical time here at Duke is coming to an end, a new journey is waiting for us just outside that door. As engineers and future leaders, we are prepared for the challenging choices that lie ahead of us.<br>Now for our memories slideshow at MEM put together by Kruti Jain. </p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>Was designated to be the MEM Hooding Ceremony speaker of my classmates at Duke University. Special Thanks to <a href="https://www.linkedi]]>
    </summary>
    
      <category term="AboutMe" scheme="http://lianliu.me/tags/AboutMe/"/>
    
      <category term="Writing" scheme="http://lianliu.me/tags/Writing/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Working with Science, Working with People]]></title>
    <link href="http://lianliu.me/2015/04/21/Working-with-Science-Working-with-People/"/>
    <id>http://lianliu.me/2015/04/21/Working-with-Science-Working-with-People/</id>
    <published>2015-04-21T02:47:25.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-05-04T05:31:01.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The presentation on Duke MEM Internship Assessment Showcase 2015 Spring. </p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TR0UEFcWhPA" target="_blank" rel="external">Presentation Video</a><br><img src="http://ww3.sinaimg.cn/mw690/72a818edgw1erd01e0lblj20zk0k00un.jpg" alt=""><br>Today I would like to talk about working with science, and working with people. This is where my passion lies. Just like this program, engineering and management. It is easier to be expert in one field. But how to bring the greater energy from the combination, is a long learning process. I’m glad to share with you how I learned to work with science and work with people. </p>
<p><img src="http://ww1.sinaimg.cn/mw690/72a818edgw1erd01g4odnj20zk0k0gnn.jpg" alt=""><br>Back in college, I learned mainly from textbook. Then I joined work, where I learned from practice. Here at MEM, I believe you have the same feeling as I do, we learn from people. </p>
<p><img src="http://ww2.sinaimg.cn/mw690/72a818edgw1erd01hqfzyj20zk0k040p.jpg" alt=""><br>This was me, four years ago, when I graduated from Fudan University. Looking back, this degree equipped me with basic qualities as an engineer; and today I am still benefiting from these skills. Here by textbook, it does not just mean paper book, or electronic versions. It means that life at campus is more straightforward comparing to real life.<br><img src="http://ww3.sinaimg.cn/mw690/72a818edgw1erd01jsnqyj20zk0k0n0z.jpg" alt=""><br>I realized the fact when I volunteered at the world exposition in my junior year of college. We had held big events at campus before, but I still felt lost when facing so many people from all around the world. They are not like formulas that you can calculate or inference! why did they just get anxious or angry at me when I was performing my duty? That was the time I decided to learn more about people. Luckily, my experience at campus and internship help me land on a job in marketing. Where, I started to swift my learning focus from working with science to working with people. </p>
<p><img src="http://ww1.sinaimg.cn/mw690/72a818edgw1erd01l949wj20zk0k0jty.jpg" alt=""><br>This picture was two years ago when I was presenting our ecommerce project to my colleagues in Henkel. Henkel is a German chemical company famous for its industrial adhesive products. My job was in China marketing department, focusing on digital marketing and media relations. Here I’d like to share this online authentication project.</p>
<p><img src="http://ww3.sinaimg.cn/mw690/72a818edgw1erd01ncknij20zk0k0tc4.jpg" alt=""><br>Fake product was a unique problem in China. We do not have much material to learn from other regions. In addition, this project involved various internal and external departments, which increased the potential conflicts.  But communication and logistic issues can be easily overcame, even for a new professional. You just need to practice and learn fast.  As for the lack of experience, we still have indirect experience to learn from. The distribution management department had dealt with offline authentication cases before; our legal department had close cooperation with legal-enforcement agencies; our sales team were familiar with the local market.<br><img src="http://ww4.sinaimg.cn/mw690/72a818edgw1erd01panf1j20zk0k00ww.jpg" alt=""><br>Another barriers in this cross department project was that people have different interests and appeals. Some department just want to shut down the fake website; some want to investigate deeper but they do not have enough budget to support. It is so important that we have marketing lead this project that we make sure all voices are heard and negotiate in between to convert conflict to contract, which eventually brought benefit to everyone.<br>The successful of this project created a marketing example in the company. Evidently it saved company losses and consolidated brand equity. Moreover, it enhanced the relationship between departments. Thanks to all the conflicts we had and the close cooperation afterwards. </p>
<p><img src="http://ww1.sinaimg.cn/mw690/72a818edgw1erd01roinoj20zk0k0aeo.jpg" alt=""><br>I summarized the key takeaways from my three-year work experience in these four words.<br>Capability, is the one crucial but I do not worry about too much. We are engineers; we have solid technical background and we learn fast.<br>Adaptability, is another essential quality for new professionals. Things change quickly when dealing with people. And we keep meeting with new situations. My responsibilities from website and email marketing to mobile devices and ecommerce. I had never expected that my job could be anything about authentication.<br>Initiative works as complement of adaptability. A lot of successful business leaders I interviewed mentioned one thing in common that they keep close track to industrial news and actively participate in networking events. This enthusiasm, or curiosity guides you to prepare in advance.<br>Finally, no matter how cruel, stressful business world is, I’ still want to keep my genuineness. It wins me trust and respect. Genuineness also means that I am willing to accept who I am. Always have a clear idea of what I want. Just do not get lost among all kinds of values and temptations. </p>
<p><img src="http://ww1.sinaimg.cn/mw690/72a818edgw1erd01tgz46j20zk0k0adc.jpg" alt=""><br>That is why I decided to come to this program, to know more about people like me.  Here I learnt more than from textbook, more than practice. Because it is the engineers have taught me, how to work with people.<br><img src="http://ww3.sinaimg.cn/mw690/72a818edgw1erd01vbybqj20zk0k0jv3.jpg" alt=""><br>I love the classroom atmosphere. Not only in class, but also the discussions throughout our case study, projects and assignments. We exchange opinions openly and look at a problem from different perspectives.<br><img src="http://ww4.sinaimg.cn/mw690/72a818edgw1erd01xzlofj20zk0k0n2d.jpg" alt=""><br>Events outside the classroom it is much more than amusement.<br>I like it when people do not judge others here. During all the remarkable activities we’ve had here, people embrace the diversified opinions and encourage all kinds of success. This encouraging spirit in return creates more opportunities and a prosperous society.<br>I will graduate in one month, and I am really grateful to what I have learnt here. I took data mining and decision models; I also took management and practicum. With all these years’ experience, I believe I am more competitive in my dreaming career, working with science, working with people.<br><img src="http://ww1.sinaimg.cn/mw690/72a818edgw1erd01zmk8dj20zk0k00tn.jpg" alt=""></p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>The presentation on Duke MEM Internship Assessment Showcase 2015 Spring. </p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TR0UEFcWhPA" ta]]>
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Color" scheme="http://lianliu.me/tags/Color/"/>
    
      <category term="Writing" scheme="http://lianliu.me/tags/Writing/"/>
    
      <category term="Presentation" scheme="http://lianliu.me/tags/Presentation/"/>
    
      <category term="AboutMe" scheme="http://lianliu.me/tags/AboutMe/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[How Do You Like It Here?]]></title>
    <link href="http://lianliu.me/2015/02/08/How-Do-You-Like-It-Here/"/>
    <id>http://lianliu.me/2015/02/08/How-Do-You-Like-It-Here/</id>
    <published>2015-02-08T03:32:21.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-02-17T02:08:15.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Half a year ago, I was frequently asked the same question, “how do you like it here?” My answer was basically the same, “I like it! People are nice here.”<br>It sounds a little disappointing, a common, general answer; but I was sincere. Based on my limited experience in this small town at that time, my strongest feeling was people were surprisingly nice! The waitress at Enzo’s helped us make a choice when we were lost in front of the huge menu. The delivery man from UPS waved to me every time he met me at my neighbourhood. Drivers at crossroads always let me pass first with a warm smile. I felt delighted and gratified although I had no furniture at home and barely knew anyone.<br>After six months of study and several trips around North Carolina, now I can contribute more to my answer.<br>I like it when people do not judge others here. I realized the fact when I was visiting a friend in New York. She was cooking for us and I asked, why do you wash vegetable like that? I usually do it this way… Suddenly I felt odd because nobody here talked like that. It had been a long time since I heard indifferent judgement from others. People respect different opinions and encourage you to use your own voice. They have various ways to define right, good and success. While in the place where I grow up, we tend to have a more monotonous set of values.<br>When I was in high school, one day my mom was talking with her American friend. The man proudly told us that his little son was determined to become a chef. We were so surprised by his contented expression since at that time my family’s biggest wish was sending me to the best college in China. We could not imagine raising a child to become a chef made someone a successful parent.<br>In my view this encouraging spirit comes from a highly developed society, where most industries and businesses have grown into relatively a matured status. Therefore people have a more comprehensive understanding of all walks of life; additionally, no matter what kind of career you choose, it will not be too difficult to obtain the resources and allies required to realize your goal. In return, more opportunities are springing out in this prosperous society; this creates a flourishing cycle of the productive force .<br>This cycle should be a natural outcome of development. So I believe someday in the future we will also have a more inclusive attitude towards others’ choices in China. For now I do enjoy our less industrialized society in some ways. Everything has huge potential to grow and no fixed pattern has formed yet. Not to mention we have the best food in the world!<br><img src="http://ww1.sinaimg.cn/bmiddle/72a818edjw1eixk1yqkhzg2074074x6q.gif" alt="Chinese Food"></p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>Half a year ago, I was frequently asked the same question, “how do you like it here?” My answer was basically the same, “I like it! Peopl]]>
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Writing" scheme="http://lianliu.me/tags/Writing/"/>
    
      <category term="AboutMe" scheme="http://lianliu.me/tags/AboutMe/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Master of Engineering Management at Duke University]]></title>
    <link href="http://lianliu.me/2015/02/05/Master-of-Engineering-Management-at-Duke-University/"/>
    <id>http://lianliu.me/2015/02/05/Master-of-Engineering-Management-at-Duke-University/</id>
    <published>2015-02-05T03:04:01.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-04-21T03:10:30.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://ww1.sinaimg.cn/mw690/72a818edjw1eoydu23tgyj211c0s0429.jpg" alt="Duke MEM T-shirt Design"></p>
<p>The latest design of MEM T-shirt: Master of Engineering Management Program.</p>
<p>And… the T-shirt!<br><img src="https://scontent-iad.xx.fbcdn.net/hphotos-xaf1/v/t1.0-9/10660268_866205750111679_5185980304862874832_n.jpg?oh=c488b4d4eadcee36d8bf9ea66d2dc0a1&amp;oe=55D163CC" alt=""></p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p><img src="http://ww1.sinaimg.cn/mw690/72a818edjw1eoydu23tgyj211c0s0429.jpg" alt="Duke MEM T-shirt Design"></p>
<p>The latest design of ME]]>
    </summary>
    
      <category term="FunFact" scheme="http://lianliu.me/tags/FunFact/"/>
    
      <category term="AboutMe" scheme="http://lianliu.me/tags/AboutMe/"/>
    
      <category term="Color" scheme="http://lianliu.me/tags/Color/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[AngryBirds x Oriental Pearl Tower]]></title>
    <link href="http://lianliu.me/2015/01/25/AngryBirds-x-Oriental-Pearl-Tower/"/>
    <id>http://lianliu.me/2015/01/25/AngryBirds-x-Oriental-Pearl-Tower/</id>
    <published>2015-01-25T05:32:50.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-01-25T06:21:48.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It has been some time. Click <a href="http://bit.ly/1tcdmuE" target="_blank" rel="external">HERE</a> to buy it in T-shirts and hoodies.<br><img src="http://ww2.sinaimg.cn/mw690/72a818edjw1eolpg1fsnpj20lc0sggp8.jpg" alt="AngryBirds x Oriental Pearl Tower"></p>
<p>Comparing with the real one.<br><img src="http://shanghailandscapes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/06/the-Oriental-Pearl-Tower-with-Huangpu-river-in-Shanghai.jpg" alt="Shanghai Oriental Pearl Tower"></p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>It has been some time. Click <a href="http://bit.ly/1tcdmuE" target="_blank" rel="external">HERE</a> to buy it in T-shirts and hoodies.<b]]>
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Color" scheme="http://lianliu.me/tags/Color/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Digital Advertising]]></title>
    <link href="http://lianliu.me/2015/01/24/Digital-Advertising/"/>
    <id>http://lianliu.me/2015/01/24/Digital-Advertising/</id>
    <published>2015-01-23T22:45:59.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-01-24T01:34:55.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>With the rising concerns about safety and privacy issues of big data analysis on the internet, do you think digital advertising will be seriously affected by policies or regulations in the near future? If no, why; if yes, what do you think should this industry do to prepare for this situation?</p>
<p>This was the question I asked to <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/profile/view?id=82282778&amp;authType=NAME_SEARCH&amp;authToken=edTS&amp;locale=en_US&amp;trk=tyah2&amp;trkInfo=tarId%3A1422059506555%2Ctas%3Aparikh%2Cidx%3A1-4-4" target="_blank" rel="external">Mr. Parikh</a> in today’s seminar, the Marketing Scientist from <a href="http://www.maxpoint.com/" target="_blank" rel="external">MaxPoint</a>. Due to my last job in digital marketing, I am always attracted by this topic. The real-time online analysis is completely changing the way of campaigns and will bring us undistracted advertising experience online. As long as it keeps anonymous, it is a most efficient way to target customers and win profits. But yes, more people are worrying about this rapid developing technology. Despite their  ignorance of this technology itself, stories like  iCloud leak and Edward Snowden just proved the growing risks of online information collection.<br>Asking me, I think it will but I do not know what to do. <em>I was born in China I never fight against policies :)</em> That is why I asked Mr. Parikh. With several years experience in digital advertising I believed he would have some deep insights on this question.<br>And he did.<br>“I wish it won’t”, he smiled. But it is possible; especially we have seen some similar cases in other countries already. For example Europe has the most strict <a href="http://www.cookielaw.org/faq/#Isthecookielawdead" target="_blank" rel="external">Cookie Laws</a>. And you can barely use Google Analytics in China due to regional restrictions. <em>Why didn’t I think about this before?! I had been suffering from it!</em> Even though the situation could be cruel, the bright side is policies having such heavy influence are usually implemented gradually, which leaves the industry adequate time to prepare. Then we will react accordingly. It is undeniable that to make money, and with the money on hand, companies need to make advertisements. Internet is the most convenient, accurate and efficient way to do it. So we will follow this path and strive for a solution. </p>
<p>I am pretty contented with this answer. It not only cleared my doubts of this industry, but also showed me a meticulous way to think. When I said yes, I believe digital advertising will be affected by policies; it was more like my gut: it caused crisis; it could be dangerous; so people are fighting against it. But he looked at a bigger picture; referred to historical and ongoing cases, which would lead the way to solutions. The logic is easy to follow and convincing, making me think I could come up with that as well. But if I could, why would I ask ;)<br>The environment I grew up in makes me worry about asking questions.  What if it is a naive question? What if I actually can solve it myself? What if the other person refuses to answer? Now you see, asking to a mature thinker teaches you to become a mature thinker. </p>
<p>And by the way, this one-hour seminar was almost filled with students’ questions from all aspects, career, MEM Program, industry, etc. Mr. Parikh insightfully answered all questions without any preparation. Very impressive. </p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>With the rising concerns about safety and privacy issues of big data analysis on the internet, do you think digital advertising will be s]]>
    </summary>
    
      <category term="FunFact" scheme="http://lianliu.me/tags/FunFact/"/>
    
      <category term="Writing" scheme="http://lianliu.me/tags/Writing/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[My Work Experience Summary]]></title>
    <link href="http://lianliu.me/2015/01/20/My-Work-Experience-Summary/"/>
    <id>http://lianliu.me/2015/01/20/My-Work-Experience-Summary/</id>
    <published>2015-01-20T01:58:32.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-01-21T00:04:19.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A brief introduction of my work experience, required by our Internship Assessment class. It explains the reasons of taking this job, introduce the company as well as the position, and the takeaways from this experience.</p>
<p>In my fourth year of college, I decided not to keep pursuing academic study in microelectronics after graduation; instead, I realized that I was more interested in meeting different people and intrigued with their unique qualities. So I believed that a marketing position would both fulfill my interest and make use of my strength. Although it was not a small transformation from engineering to an interpersonal job, I still got an internship in a corporate communication department due to my experience in the campus TV station and other students’ activities. This position provided me with a basic understanding of the operation of an international company, strengthened my communication skills, and confirmed my determination to work in a marketing department. After the six-month internship, I applied for a marketing executive position with Henkel China. This position was mainly responsible for online marketing in the Greater China area. Thanks to my internship experience and the decently conducted interviews, I finally got this job.</p>
<p>Henkel is a German chemical company well known for its adhesive products and home care cosmetics. In China, Henkel has shown strong growth in the industrial adhesives market since 2000. The new century witnessed an increasing number of companies benefiting from the rapid development of the internet, which made Henkel, a traditional industrial business, also consider keeping up with the times. Therefore, Henkel China decided to establish an e-business function in its marketing department; and I was honored to be hired, mainly in charge of this function.</p>
<p>Initially my job included maintaining the corporate websites and conducting online campaigns. But just as the rapid growth of the internet, new problems related to online issues kept springing up unexpectedly. During the first two years of this job, I got the chance to implement various projects such as search engine optimization, online authentication and ecommerce management. Some of these projects were entirely new to the company. Luckily my boss always encouraged us to learn from different sources, which made this job challenging and worthwhile. As time went on, I became more familiar with the company operation and then was appointed to also take responsibility for the media relation issues. Contact with media was more complicated than I expected, since media agencies tended to hold their own values and ideas tightly. It required thorough communication tactics to consociate journalists from different agencies to benefit the company’s reputation.</p>
<p>One of the most important things I have learned from my three-year work experience is to always prepare yourself to adapt to this changing society. Even when you feel that everything is under control, it is better to get equipped for what might happen next. I can still remember that when I first entered the e-business field in 2011, basically most of the job was to promote the corporate websites and to maintain email marketing. But it only took less than a year for the company to shift its emphasis to mobile devices and ecommerce. During the second and third years, the boundary between online of offline marketing became more and more ambiguous; integrated marketing required collaboration from all functions of the marketing department. Consequently, my responsibilities changed as well.</p>
<p>Another takeaway I received from this job was how to balance various voices in the work place. Comparably, academic study is more straightforward since you only need to consider gaining good grades; and most of the time you just interact with classmates and professors. While during work, generally there is more than one project going on; and they usually involve tangling with different departments and bureaus who have their own interests and purposes. A coordinator in these kinds of projects should not only assure all voiced are heard, but also strive for greater benefits for the company. </p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>A brief introduction of my work experience, required by our Internship Assessment class. It explains the reasons of taking this job, intr]]>
    </summary>
    
      <category term="AboutMe" scheme="http://lianliu.me/tags/AboutMe/"/>
    
      <category term="Writing" scheme="http://lianliu.me/tags/Writing/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Prepare to Manage and Lead]]></title>
    <link href="http://lianliu.me/2015/01/20/Prepare-to-Manage-and-Lead/"/>
    <id>http://lianliu.me/2015/01/20/Prepare-to-Manage-and-Lead/</id>
    <published>2015-01-19T23:58:21.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-01-20T02:45:30.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is the first assignment of our Management class. We need to read a story about Eugene Kranz before answering the following questions. The Story is from Michael Useem’s book, <a href="https://books.google.com/books?id=yv1E1-7vINYC&amp;pg=PT72&amp;lpg=PT72&amp;dq=eugene+kranz+returns+apollo+13+to+earth&amp;source=bl&amp;ots=05--zIVYHl&amp;sig=i2YqU52zGXSv-I0euAXzisgQSKA&amp;hl=en&amp;sa=X&amp;ei=z6i9VP2aEYGcNrrpgpgK&amp;ved=0CCYQ6AEwAQ#v=onepage&amp;q=eugene%20kranz%20returns%20apollo%2013%20to%20earth&amp;f=false" target="_blank" rel="external">The Leadership Moment</a>, <strong>Chapter 3, Eugene Kranz Returns Apollo 13 to Earth</strong>.<br>The first two questions are about your understanding of the story. The third question is about yourself, to evaluate your strengths and shortcomings as a manager or a leader.<br><strong>Instructor</strong>: Professor Ted Ryan</p>
<ol>
<li><p><strong>PRE-CRISIS Preparation</strong>: In his two years as Flight Director prior to Apollo 13’s crisis, Kranz implemented a number of innovative organizational initiatives.  What were Kranz’ key organizational initiatives – BEFORE the crisis occurred – that turned out to be critical to the successful return of Apollo 13?  For each innovative initiative you cite, state why/how it became critical to Apollo 13’s safe return.<br><em>Note: These initiatives were “management” and/or “leadership” initiatives – but for now, don’t worry about whether an initiative was more management or leadership.</em></p>
<p>First, Kranz had <strong>comprehensive understanding of his team members</strong>. He knew not only their strengths, but also their shortcomings and how to stimulate their full potential based on his understanding. Therefore, in a time-critical and true emergency environment, Kranz could assign the right people on right positions. For example, when recruiting Bill Peters from the Gold Team, despite the doubt from other flight directors, Kranz believed that Peters’ exceptional experience would be crucial to the crisis, while he might need someone “to bring out the pieces”. The same situation happened when recruiting John Aaron as well. Naturally, these people did not let Kranz down. We can say that, everyone in the team was dealing with the task he/she was expert in. Consequently each function of the team just needed to focus on its own problem. The absence of disturbance was one of the key factors to make prompt and accurate decisions.<br>In addition to Kranz’ own familiarity with the team, he particularly devoted attention to the <strong>team’s efficiency when working together</strong>. As mentioned in the case, “its members had developed the ability to compensate for each other when the chips get down”. His effort included encouraging the team members to know one another, and then to communicate and trust one another. He arranged his flight teams into their own baseball league and the team challenged the astronaut teams on the football field. The active team-building events consolidated the team together and established strong reliance among multiple teams. As a result, even under the most critical circumstance, people in Room 210 functioned methodically. Similarly, during the early period of the crisis, Kranz could restructure the team and regroup people across levels, between outside contractors and inside employees without concerns.<br>These two innovative initiatives guaranteed both Kranz and his team the access to all required resources. And these people had been long prepared for working in the most efficient way. Therefore they could reach an optimal conclusion under severe pressure.</p>
</li>
<li><p><strong>Kranz’ Attributes/Behaviors</strong>:  Our reading describes how Kranz prepared himself technically for his responsibilities as Flight Director.  He was superbly trained and had great technological expertise.  However, it is clear that Kranz’ technological competence alone was not enough for him to lead Apollo 13 safely back to earth.  What were Kranz’ most important NON-technical characteristics that enabled him to lead Apollo 13 to a successful conclusion?</p>
<p>First, Kranz’ <strong>calmness</strong> was crucial of successfully managing this crisis. Although technological expertise and comprehensive experience were the foundation of calmness, this characteristic required continual training other than growing naturally. Throughout the crisis, Kranz kept seeking orderly analysis. Other than blind optimism, it ensured that Kranz could objectively evaluate the situation and then make accurate decision.<br>We cannot neglect Kranz’ <strong>infectious personal</strong> characteristic as well, which was shown in many details during the accident. For example, As soon as Kranz realized the sign of panic in Mission control, he started to influence the team with encouraging suggestions. “Let’s solve the problem.” “Let’s not make it any worse by guessing”. During the crisis, he exhorted his team to concentrate on “what was working, rather than focusing on what was not”. He believed optimistic might not be sufficiency to a favorable outcome, but definitely necessity. So he used his influence to arouse the team’s morale. The smooth cooperation of the Tiger Team under such huge pressure proved this point of view. </p>
</li>
<li><p><strong>Your Readiness to Manage and Lead</strong>:  You may not face a crisis as severe as a crippled spaceship, with a crew in jeopardy.  However, as an engineering manager, you will quickly face serious challenges that will test you.  Suppose you were faced with a serious organizational challenge today.  How ready are you? </p>
<p>a. List three <strong>positive personal non-technical qualities/behaviors</strong> that would help you manage/lead others, especially in difficult circumstances. For each of these qualities/ behaviors, describe a practical step you can take to strengthen them further.</p>
<p>i.    <strong>Calmness</strong><br>Kranz’ successful story proved how important calmness could be, especially in critical circumstances. I believe most of my calmness comes from my various work and projects experience. As analyzed in Kranz’ case, this positive attitude usually based on one’s qualification in certain situations. Or it will become blind optimism, which cannot be helpful at all.<br>Therefore I need to equip myself with adequate industrial knowledge. Then cultivate the habits of simulating potential hardness and seeking for multiple solutions. Theses habits will prepare me for different kinds of unexpected difficulties and accidents.</p>
<p>ii.    <strong>Accountable</strong><br>Accountable is a reputation earned through long-time effective work, strong team spirit and last but not the least, honesty towards failures. This reputation assures more challenging management positions when accidents happen.<br>At present, being accountable is relatively easy because the projects I have dealt with are less complex. While I should regard them as good opportunities to strengthen my accountability. A strictly conducted agenda is definitely good to keep the project on time. Making reasonable commitment is more practical in crisis than setting unrealistic goals. Getting to know the team eliminates the risk when working together. As a student or entry level employee, mistakes and failures usually do not cause chaotic consequences. But learning from them is beneficial in the long term. This attitude will also increase the reputation of accountability. </p>
<p>iii.    <strong>Structure</strong><br>The characteristic of being organized can effectively avoid panic, confusion and flurry when crisis comes. Academic study is a well structured environment where classes are arranged at fixed time and syllabuses show exactly the tasks in the semester. I believe students tend to have a good structured analysis methodology. While in real working environment, more constraints, roles, resources will be involved.<br>Actually the project charter we write in every case study report is very helpful to strengthen the ability of structurally thinking. It is t. At first this section might be regarded just as a compulsory part of the report. But as time goes by I realize that a project charter is not just for the readers to grasp a rough idea of the situation. It shows my understanding of this project. To compose a concise project charter instructs me to read the case with structured purposes from the very beginning.<br>In addition to the case studies required by classes, I can also develop this characteristic through learning my own cases. The stories can come from news, exchanging experience with others and extending the classroom study from documents. </p>
<p>b. List three of your <strong>weaker qualities/behaviors</strong> – areas of vulnerability that you will need to change and develop in order to manage/lead others effectively, especially in difficult circumstances. Refer to your Personal Development Plan.  For each of these qualities/behaviors, describe a practical step you can take to strengthen them.</p>
<p>i.    <strong>Flexibility</strong><br>I do like well-organized projects. As a result, it may cause the lack of flexibility.<br>First of all, overcome the upset feelings towards changes. With a positive attitude to uncertainties, I shall strength my adaptability through experiences. Try not to focus on the events I am used to. New challenges bring fresh opportunities and increase the possibility of meeting with changes. With more experience of dealing with changes, I shall become more skilled at anticipating potential incidents. </p>
<p>ii.    <strong>Patience</strong><br>One of the vulnerabilities I have now is that I tend to become impatient when facing people with totally different background from me, especially when we fail to understand each other after several attempts.<br>Considering the responsibilities of a manager or a leader, patience is so important in that this character is always tangling with people from different industries with various personalities. And the key mission is to unite these people working together towards a common purpose.<br>To get in touch with people from other industries will obviously be helpful. It will broaden my understanding of different fields. Possible channels include personal network, industrial events and public media. When conducting these interactions, keep in mind that the conversation should not be limited to our shared topics. Instead, I need to encourage the other person to talk about his or her work experience and insights on the industry. It will not only enrich my knowledge, but also train my skills of obtaining brand new ideas. When misunderstanding or confusion occurs, try to use another way of expression or seek for an analogy familiar by both sides, other than emphasizing the same sentence repeatedly.</p>
<p>iii.    <strong>Maturity</strong><br>I do not think maturity equals to insensibility. Instead, it is more about regulate the emotion, especially under severe pressures. Comparing to calmness, which is mainly towards the situation, maturity includes a comprehensive management of emotions for events as well as human beings.<br>When mingling with different people, pay attention to their characteristics and behavior pattern. This experience will help to form thorough tactics of communication and interaction. This ability can also be cultivated through textbook learning. One of the recommendations is <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eric_Berne" target="_blank" rel="external">Eric Berne</a>’s <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Transactional_analysis" target="_blank" rel="external">Transactional Analysis</a>.<br>In addition, a proper way of relieving stress should be developed. It can be reading, exercise or meditation.</p>
</li>
</ol>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>This is the first assignment of our Management class. We need to read a story about Eugene Kranz before answering the following questions]]>
    </summary>
    
      <category term="AboutMe" scheme="http://lianliu.me/tags/AboutMe/"/>
    
      <category term="Writing" scheme="http://lianliu.me/tags/Writing/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Case Study from Marketing Class]]></title>
    <link href="http://lianliu.me/2015/01/15/Case-Study-from-Marketing-Class/"/>
    <id>http://lianliu.me/2015/01/15/Case-Study-from-Marketing-Class/</id>
    <published>2015-01-15T02:31:27.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-01-15T04:53:01.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Marketing was quite an inspiring class for me, even considering that I had been working with a competitive marketing team for three years.<br>Our instructor, Professor Kathie Amato had all kinds of incredible ideas to arouse people’s initiative. During the four-month’s study, in addition to the regular lectures, we watched countless fascinating commercials, had snacks to keep the colorful packages as name tags, did a double blind test among different brands soda which is exactly the thing I wished to do for a long time. And yes, my classmates continually surprised me with their creative point of views!<br>The cases we studied covered industries including food, transportation, medicine, travel and FMCG. We were required to deliver three slides after self studying each case. Then we would discuss, or should I say, fight against each other, about what we had digged out from the case. It was really insightful to have tens of people with all kinds of backgrounds sitting together, sharing opinions. I used to believe I was the one thinking out of the box. <strong>But here I realized that there is always a box out of my box!</strong><br>At first it was not easy to squeeze all the conclusions into only three slides. Right, lack of concision is the sign of inexperience. But gradually, I could deal with not only the content itself, no matter it was quantitative analysis or qualitative statement, but also the artwork! I just have an obsession with well-arranged, good-looking slides design. Maybe that is one of the assets I have recieved from marketing experience. </p>
<h3 id="Starbucks">Starbucks</h3>
<p><img src="http://ww3.sinaimg.cn/mw690/72a818edjw1eo9zxyfi0tj21kw0w0dwp.jpg" alt=""></p>
<h3 id="Mountain_Man_Beer_Company">Mountain Man Beer Company</h3>
<p><img src="http://ww2.sinaimg.cn/mw690/72a818edjw1eo9zxvzbanj21kw0w0wva.jpg" alt=""></p>
<h3 id="Molson">Molson</h3>
<p><img src="http://ww4.sinaimg.cn/mw690/72a818edjw1eo9zxths0lj21kw0w0tm7.jpg" alt=""></p>
<h3 id="MedicinesCom">MedicinesCom</h3>
<p><img src="http://ww1.sinaimg.cn/mw690/72a818edjw1eo9zxr9p1hj21kw0w07mc.jpg" alt=""></p>
<h3 id="American_Airline’s">American Airline’s</h3>
<p><img src="http://ww4.sinaimg.cn/mw690/72a818edjw1eo9zxownsnj21kw0w04e7.jpg" alt=""></p>
<h3 id="Uniliver_in_Brazil">Uniliver in Brazil</h3>
<p><img src="http://ww3.sinaimg.cn/mw690/72a818edjw1eo9zy11fiij21kw0w0k5v.jpg" alt=""></p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>Marketing was quite an inspiring class for me, even considering that I had been working with a competitive marketing team for three years]]>
    </summary>
    
      <category term="CaseStudy" scheme="http://lianliu.me/tags/CaseStudy/"/>
    
      <category term="Color" scheme="http://lianliu.me/tags/Color/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Comic Book in New York]]></title>
    <link href="http://lianliu.me/2015/01/10/Comic-Book-in-New-York/"/>
    <id>http://lianliu.me/2015/01/10/Comic-Book-in-New-York/</id>
    <published>2015-01-10T03:53:42.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-01-20T02:52:33.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In many ways, New York City is quite like Shanghai. The skyscrapers drop your hat when you try to count the floors; the crowd pushes you to move no matter you want or not; the luxury brands shine in windows innocently towards tourists from all around the world; the traffic is always terrible in downtown area; people with different backgrounds and religions gather in their own group but get along with each others as well.<br>I do enjoy the clear blue sky here, which is becoming more and more rare in Shanghai these years. If ignoring some of the old, sticky, creepy subway stations, this should be a nice city to live in.<br>Anyway, I properly used my imaginations to the pictures taken in New York City. Or there would be no fun at all to show those monotonous METROPOLISES images.<br>By the way, super fan of Marvel here :)</p>
<p><img src="http://ww4.sinaimg.cn/mw690/72a818edjw1eo48m0oghnj20sg0lcwk3.jpg" alt="spiderman1"></p>
<p><img src="http://ww2.sinaimg.cn/mw690/72a818edjw1eo48mjqbtsj20lc0sgq9r.jpg" alt="spiderman2"></p>
<p><img src="http://ww1.sinaimg.cn/mw690/72a818edjw1eo48nbk7auj20sg0lc77q.jpg" alt="loki"></p>
<p><img src="http://ww3.sinaimg.cn/mw690/72a818edjw1eo48nfge9hj20lc0sgaev.jpg" alt="thor"></p>
<p><img src="http://ww1.sinaimg.cn/mw690/72a818edjw1eo48mt3fysj20lc0sggqc.jpg" alt="hawkeye"></p>
<p><img src="http://ww3.sinaimg.cn/mw690/72a818edjw1eo48ma28rij20sg0lcjwj.jpg" alt="baymax1"></p>
<p><img src="http://ww3.sinaimg.cn/mw690/72a818edjw1eo48lt8bfmj20lc0sggqw.jpg" alt="baymax2"></p>
<p><img src="http://ww3.sinaimg.cn/mw690/72a818edjw1eo48lofrd4j20lc0sg0x4.jpg" alt="hulk"></p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>In many ways, New York City is quite like Shanghai. The skyscrapers drop your hat when you try to count the floors; the crowd pushes you ]]>
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Color" scheme="http://lianliu.me/tags/Color/"/>
    
      <category term="Travel" scheme="http://lianliu.me/tags/Travel/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Role of Important US Organizations in the Fight Against Ebola]]></title>
    <link href="http://lianliu.me/2014/11/25/Role-of-Important-US-Organizations-in-the-Fight-Against-Ebola/"/>
    <id>http://lianliu.me/2014/11/25/Role-of-Important-US-Organizations-in-the-Fight-Against-Ebola/</id>
    <published>2014-11-25T02:18:34.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-01-20T02:50:14.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is the final project from our Data Mining course in Fall semester 2014. It was really exciting to have thirty students from this class study on one topic, Ebola. Especially at that time it was quite a hot topic in the news. Professor Egger divided this huge topic into several sub topics so each of us can focus on one aspect of the study. And mine was <strong>Role of Important US Organizations in the Fight Against Ebola</strong>. </p>
<ul>
<li>This project aimed to study the extent that the financial and medical assistance from the U.S. will help control the epidemic; furthermore, the project intended to identify whether the promised support will be sufficient in the next 6 – 12 months. </li>
<li>An SEIR model was built up to estimate the future numbers of cases and to evaluate the amount of assistance that will be needed. </li>
<li>Considering that the U.S., U.K. and France are dividing some responsibilities for fighting the Ebola outbreak in West Africa along colonial-era lines2, this study mainly focused on the situation in Liberia; while general analysis on Guinea and Sierra Leone was also conducted.</li>
<li>All analysis was based on data available as of November 15, 2014.</li>
</ul>
<p>We were required to study independently on our own topics and make a poster showing all our study results. At the final presentation, we had fifteen minutes to illustrate our study using the poster; meanwhile, we had the opportunity to share our takeaways with our peers.<br>I have to say that this poster is much more delicate when seeing in screen than printed. But on the other hand, I obtained the experience of designing a professional sized poster. One of the features I was most proud of was that I used QR code to present my references instead of the traditional URLs. Obviously it is much more convenient for the audience to scan the QR code when viewing the poster. Maybe it will become a trend in the near future. </p>
<p><strong>Instructor</strong>: Professor Daniel Egger<br><img src="http://ww2.sinaimg.cn/mw690/72a818edjw1eofrv6xdtkj23k02o0u0y.jpg" alt="Role of Important US Organizations in the Fight Against Ebola"></p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>This is the final project from our Data Mining course in Fall semester 2014. It was really exciting to have thirty students from this cla]]>
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Color" scheme="http://lianliu.me/tags/Color/"/>
    
      <category term="Data" scheme="http://lianliu.me/tags/Data/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[CHRYSLER AND BMW: TRITEC ENGINE JOINT VENTURE (Section)]]></title>
    <link href="http://lianliu.me/2014/11/06/Project-Management-Case-Study/"/>
    <id>http://lianliu.me/2014/11/06/Project-Management-Case-Study/</id>
    <published>2014-11-05T17:03:30.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-04-21T03:09:29.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is a section from one of our Project Management course team assignments.<br>This consulting report is based on the case <a href="http://www.hbs.edu/faculty/Pages/item.aspx?num=516" target="_blank" rel="external">Chrysler and BMW: Tritec Engine Joint Venture</a> by H. Kent Bowen and Courtney Purrington</p>
<p>Our team were assigned to present our study result during the class. I attached the presentation slides at the end of this report.</p>
<p><strong>Created by</strong><br>Master of Engineering Management Program,<br>Duke University<br><strong>Class of 2013</strong>: Akash Gupta, Aaron Shakin<br><strong>Class of 2014</strong>: Mohammad Ali Raahim, Lian Liu</p>
<h2 id="Executive_Summary">Executive Summary</h2>
<p>Our team was contracted by Tritec, a team formed by the joint venture between Chrysler and BMW to select an appropriate solution for the engine block sealing design. The purpose of the joint venture was to capitalize on the opportunities in Asia and Latin America for low cost engines ranging in size from 1.0 – 1.6 liters. After discussing, the joint team decided to establish an engine plant in Brazil, as Chrysler believed other emerging countries were too risky and the overall project would be led by Jack Smith.<br>Our team needed to analyze and resolve the differences between the product engineering and the advanced manufacturing team. The advanced manufacturing team believed that the lower tie bar design selected by the product engineering team is impractical, as it would necessitate reinventing part of the machining process, which would be difficult.<br>We used a four-fold method to define success and select the best design. Based on our findings, our recommendation is the bedplate design, since it proved to be the most favorable option in three of these five categories.<br>… …</p>
<h2 id="Project_Charter">Project Charter</h2>
<p>Approval: The proposed plan would need a formal approval from the Tritec Management. Approval will depend on the feasibility of the analysis presented in the report and the consent of the product engineering and advanced manufacturing teams who are primary stakeholders.<br>Resources: The resources for development of each selected project type will be assigned based on approval from management. Additional resources could be assigned subject to approval and requirement.<br>Project Manager: The Project Manager (PM) for the joint venture between BMW and Chrysler is Jack Smith. He is considered a talented manufacturing engineer with advanced degrees in mechanical engineering. He was concerned about his lack of experience but the management assured him he would be provided with necessary resources.</p>
<h3 id="Problem_Statement">Problem Statement</h3>
<p><strong>Current State:</strong> Tritec is currently facing a dilemma with regard to the engine block design. The product engineering team believed that a lower tie bar design would help decrease anticipated warranty costs and would be more reliable, while the advanced manufacturing team believed that this design would necessitate the reinvention of the machining process which would create an added challenge.<br>Future State: We envision that the selected design will satisfy both the product engineering team and the advanced manufacturing engineering team based on the thorough analysis. The chosen design would also help Tritec develop an engine that would make the joint venture achieve profitable growth with less risk.<br><strong>Constraints:</strong> The limitations of risk, design feasibility and future impact were among the constraints considered.  Time and budget are perhaps the most important constraints in this endeavor.  There are check points to gauge progress throughout the building process of the engines, but ultimately, it is imperative for Tritec to implement a sealing design that helps achieve its  mission of building “the world’s lowest overall cost engine business in the city of Campo Largo, Brazil by July 2000” (mission idea is from Team 8’s report; quote from page 8 of the case). </p>
<h2 id="Design_Selection_Approach">Design Selection Approach</h2>
<p>The design selection approach was based on a number of metrics. In order to arrive at the recommended design, a comparative analysis was carried out to weigh the strengths and weaknesses of each design. Using this approach, the first order of business was to define an empirical criteria/definition for a successful design within the constraints of the Tritec team’s design and manufacturing capabilities. Keeping the available data in mind, the following criteria were defined:</p>
<ol>
<li>Conformance/positive impact on the 12-panel objectives</li>
<li>Design favorability, in terms of investment, variable cost, manufacturing, workload etc.</li>
<li>Sealing design and process risk</li>
<li>Warranty assessment</li>
</ol>
<p>The design that performed best on the above set of criteria was deemed as the most suitable one for the project team to pursue.<br>Conformance/positive impact on the 12-panel objectives<br>Exhibit 18 scored each design approach on the 12-panel objectives spelled out to gauge the progress of the project. The original tie bar design served as the reference, while the two alternatives either got a 0 (indicating performance at-par with the original design), a positive (indicating a relative advantage) or a negative (indicating a relative disadvantage) on each of the 12 objectives.<br>In our approach, we summed up the impact ratings to arrive at a final score for each design. By default, the original tie bar design had a score of 0, while analysis of the other two designs revealed the following:</p>
<ul>
<li>Bedplate design had a score of -1</li>
<li>Rear retainer style had a score of -4</li>
<li>Conclusion: In terms of positive impact on the 12-panel objectives, the original tie bar design performed the best with a score of 0. The bedplate design, however, was a close second.<h3 id="Design_favorability">Design favorability</h3>
Next, each of the designs was evaluated on the basis of favorability. The data was obtained from Exhibit 17. A higher summary total score indicated more favorability. The number was obtained by taking a weighted sum of the ratings assigned to each design approach based on a number of practical implementation aspects. The following results were gleaned from the data:</li>
<li>Bedplate design had the highest summary total of 158, followed by the rear retainer style design with 137</li>
<li>Conclusion: Bedplate design has the most favorable design review</li>
</ul>
<p>… …</p>
<h3 id="Assumptions_used_in_the_approach">Assumptions used in the approach</h3>
<ol>
<li>It was assumed that the 4.7L comparison of bore centers and access issues will not reveal any risk, thus arriving at a total process risk score of 682 for the bedplate design. As the design in question was not the leading performer in this category, the assumption did not have any impact on the result. </li>
<li>The “?” for the timing objective in Exhibit 18 was assumed to have a value of 0. Again, assuming it was either an advantage or disadvantage would not have had any impact on the conclusion derived from the 12-panel criterion.</li>
<li>The supplier tooling cost in the case of bedplate is assumed to be the same as the other two designs ($307,000).</li>
<li>The variable costs remain the same for each of the five years considered in the cost analysis.<br>Evaluation of Project Procedure and Management Process </li>
</ol>
<h2 id="Management_Group">Management Group</h2>
<p>The management group from the very beginning of this project lacked effective communication and interactive approaches with team members. More often than not, the team members were speculating the reasons for unexpected results, instead of being involved in the decision making. For example, Chrysler held the very first meeting with BMW before the team reached to any other companies. BMW Board Director Dr. Reitzle, then accepted Chrysler’s proposal despite the objectives from his engineers.<br>These assertive decisions brought some unforeseen trouble when proceeding with the project. As we can see now, the successor team was not satisfied with the outcome from the predecessor team, since their opinion was not considered thoroughly. Additionally, the overlooking of team members’ comments reduced their loyalty to the company and consequently compromised the prestige of the management group. </p>
<h3 id="Team_Structure_and_Management">Team Structure and Management</h3>
<p>From Exhibits 5, 6 and 7 we can tell that, although each company accounted for half of the Joint Venture Steering Committee, more than two thirds of the Tritec staff leaders were from Chrysler, further imbalanced by recent staff recruits. This skewed organization chart meant that when the committee was negotiating the proposal for reaching an agreement beneficial to both sides, the implementation would likely face resistance from the execution teams either due to the different interests or different corporate cultures.<br>Another considerable problem from the team structure was that most of the execution team leaders had ten years or even more than twenty years of experience in this field, while the project manager, Jack Smith was only 33 years old and had been recently selected to run Chrysler’s van assembly plant. This disparity in experience would make it difficult for the project manager to have his decisions carried out effectively. Chrysler did provide Smith with experienced people in this project as promised, but their experience may not be entirely beneficial with a young project manager. </p>
<h3 id="Project_Manager">Project Manager</h3>
<p>Some issues regarding the project manager’s fit with this joint venture and his approach to situations he encountered may have inhibited the ability of the project to run seamlessly.  To begin with, the project manager, Jack Smith was not involved in this project until November 1996, which was almost one year after the first meeting between Chrysler and BMW. Before he joined, the engineers from both teams had already gone through some of the design details and reached an agreement to some extent. The project manager’s absence from the early period of a project led to inadequate understanding of the project’s scope. Despite the fact that Smith joined the project shortly before the agreement was signed, it still took substantial time for him to become familiar with the team and their ideas. To a certain degree, this resulted in subsequent conflicts and inefficient communication afterwards.<br>Furthermore, in a cross-functional team, especially one that has members from two companies with different corporate cultures, the project manager is particularly responsible for the team’s collaboration as well as project control. Although Smith had education and plant experience in mechanical engineering, he lacked sufficient capability in running large, complex operations. The approaches he adopted to manage the team, such as the creation of a Tritec contract book and having many meetings and workshops were techniques based on coping with ideal circumstances, without consideration of the actual situation. The revisions of the contract book proved that Smith was willing to allow proper evaluations and corresponding adjustments according to the feedback; but undoubtedly this protracted delivery had lost much of the impact on some early design decisions. </p>
<h3 id="Suggested_Actions_for_Successful_Implementation">Suggested Actions for Successful Implementation</h3>
<p>In view of the above mentioned facts, and to ensure this project moves forward smoothly, we have four suggestions for procedures and management processes as follows.</p>
<ol>
<li>Make a decision of the sealing design as soon as possible. Since points of view have been expressed sufficiently, a final decision is possible with mutual understanding using the detailed analysis demonstrated above. </li>
<li>Explore a more effective communication approach between the management group and the execution teams. Instead of frequent dogmatic meetings, the management should pay more attention to their employees and make sure the decisions are understood by everyone involved. </li>
<li>Improve the team dynamics, especially for the interaction between the Advanced Manufacturing Engineering team and the other engineers. Moving the team off-site in the middle of the project is not a good first option; but technology and commuting support can be optimized if it is needed. </li>
<li>Support the current project manager with team alignment by providing the assistance of a senior employee with more practical experience in cross-functional team management. </li>
</ol>
<h2 id="Risks_and_Best_Practices_for_Addressing_Them">Risks and Best Practices for Addressing Them</h2>
<p>While the bedplate design appears to have more advantages than the other two alternatives, it does not come without risks and potential drawbacks.  One of these risks is the condensed time frame for redesigning the lower end of the engine block.  To overcome this risk, staff would need to be reallocated to concentrate on designing in order to meet the “OK to tool” milestone. Reassigning individuals to design roles who have minimal training and experience presents another risk.  Therefore, project manager, Jack Smith should also consider hiring new employees specialized in design.  While it would be costly to hire new designers to help accelerate this stage, there still is an estimated $5 million in reserve, which could be put towards bringing on extra staff to compensate for lost time.<br>The bedplate design comes with an added $8 million involved in bedplate machining that is not required for the other two designs.  Bedplate machining would also entail two extra assembly lines in the machining process which increases the amount of interdependency involved and the likelihood of delays.  Tritec can attempt to find a reliable subcontractor to machine the bedplate at a lower cost than Tritec would otherwise have, for purchasing the extra machining equipment and doing the machining of the bedplate themselves.  Finding a vendor that already has the necessary equipment for making the bedplate and experienced machinists with this step, would alleviate risks involved in bedplate manufacturing and eliminate one of the added assembly lines, as long as there would not be any excessive delays involved for order processing and shipping time.<br>Another risk involved in the investment for the bedplate is the unknown cost of supplier tooling.  As shown in Exhibit 13, the supplier tooling is listed as “TBD” for the bedplate while the other two designs have costs of $307,000.  To address the risk involved in this uncertain expense, Tritec must determine approximate costs for supplier tooling options that are available, and then make a conservative estimate based on this data, so that the expense can be factored into the projected investment.  If the cost is on the same order of magnitude as the supplier tooling costs for the other two design alternatives, then it will not have a significant impact on the total investment, and there would still be some reserve funds remaining.</p>
<h2 id="Lessons_Learned">Lessons Learned</h2>
<p>This case was invaluable to us because of the added stipulation of not being able to communicate face to face with teammates.  Since many project teams and consulting companies have individuals in different locations, meetings where all members are physically present are not always practical, particularly for tasks that can be orchestrated remotely.  We treated this process similarly to the how we conducted previous team meetings for prior cases, except in this situation, our meetings were done through Google Hangout sessions.  While it seemed as though this requirement would present an extra challenge, we felt that we could still turn in quality work, as we had before.  In some respects, meeting remotely made it less of a challenge to arrange meetings, since all group members did not need to be in the same location.<br>Having a few weeks available to complete this assignment, we found it advantageous to make the most of the time available.  On previous cases, there seemed to be an excess of work that was saved until the day before the deadline, which inevitably prevented us from doing the most thorough job we could, with proofreading and formatting of the report.  We learned that it would be helpful to establish a deadline for completing a draft of the report a full week before it was due, to provide us with ample time for revising it.  Furthermore, our team was assigned to potentially present on this case, meaning that we needed to factor time into the preparation process for creating a comprehensive and captivating presentation of our group strategy in this case.  Projects in the workplace may often have long term schedules, but as we have realized, beginning the process earlier, creates a less stressful atmosphere at the deadline, particularly when other pressing assignments show up with little or no warning.<br>Finally, we learned to cooperate with our partner team, Team 8, during preparation of this case.  Since one group would be presenting on behalf of both teams, it was imperative for us to share ideas with Team 8 in order to get the benefit of having eight individuals to collaborate with.  We decided that it would be best to come up with solutions to the case as two independent teams in order to generate alternative ways of choosing a strategy and then have a large Google Hangout session with all members from both teams, to see what each team had come up with.  This method would allow the two teams to critique the other’s approach and offer suggestions as constructive feedback from peers who are familiar with the information of the case.  Furthermore, having the other team’s perspective could give us new ideas about the case, which could be incorporated into our presentation and evaluated beside our initial methodology.  Having more mental capacity than any individual can provide is one important advantage of working in teams.  Therefore, having eight individuals collaborating increased the potential from </p>
<h2 id="Summary">Summary</h2>
<p>Tritec Motors’ initial lower tie bar engine block sealing design was deemed inadequate because it would not be able to keep up with the high volume production that was needed.  The design process was difficult to replicate if it was going to be done at different stations.  Without consistency in machining, quality assurance for this design would become an issue and as much as 25 percent of the cylinder blocks would need to be discarded.  This was a significant concern, which could lead to an unwanted increase in costs.<br>Two alternative designs of a rear retainer style and a bedplate design were proposed by project engineers and compared against several criteria: maximum positive impact on the 12 panel objectives (Exhibit 18), most favorable design based on factors such as sealing, design workload, assembly, and service (Exhibit 17), lowest risk with respect to design and process (Exhibits 15 and 16), and lowest amount of warranty conditions per thousand (Exhibit 14).  For the 12 panel objectives, the original tie bar design proved to be more preferable than both the bedplate and the rear retainer designs.  With respect to the factors analyzed in Exhibit 17, the bedplate design had an overall score which was higher than both alternatives.  The bedplate was the option with the lowest risk under Design Failure Mode and Effects Analysis and the second lowest risk under Process Failure Mode and Effects Analysis.  The bedplate design also finished with best warranty score, having the lowest estimated conditions per thousand.  Since the bedplate design proved to be the superior engine sealing design option in three of the five distinct categories and neither of the other two alternatives scored the highest in more than one of the categories, it was a clear decision that the bedplate design should be chosen.<br>In addition, management could be improved in this project with better communication as well as superior collaboration and support between the project staff and project manager, Jack Smith.   With management concerns addressed and risks mitigated appropriately, selection of the bedplate engine block sealing design should enable the Tritec engine joint venture to be a successful project that is capable of being completed within both time and budget constraints.</p>
<p>Looking back at the slides I made for our presentation, it appears not professional at all! At least I do not feel proud of this work as I did several months ago. Well, the structure is easy to follow; the content is concise. But I believe I can come up with better design. So it should be pasted here to remind me that, I need to work harder to satisfy myself in the future.</p>
<p><img src="http://ww1.sinaimg.cn/mw690/72a818edjw1eofqwplrisj217z334e81.jpg" alt="Presentation Slides"></p>
<hr>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>This is a section from one of our Project Management course team assignments.<br>This consulting report is based on the case <a href="htt]]>
    </summary>
    
      <category term="CaseStudy" scheme="http://lianliu.me/tags/CaseStudy/"/>
    
      <category term="Color" scheme="http://lianliu.me/tags/Color/"/>
    
      <category term="Writing" scheme="http://lianliu.me/tags/Writing/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[My Visualized Resume]]></title>
    <link href="http://lianliu.me/2014/10/20/My-Visualized-Resume/"/>
    <id>http://lianliu.me/2014/10/20/My-Visualized-Resume/</id>
    <published>2014-10-20T01:15:29.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-01-20T02:48:26.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I created my visualized resume through <a href="http://www.wordle.net/" target="_blank" rel="external">Wordle</a>. Yes, I have passion for visualizing everything! Check <a href="http://lianliu.me/2014/11/24/Role-of-Important-US-Organizations-in-the-Fight-Against-Ebola/" target="_blank" rel="external">here</a> for my poster design of Ebola epidemic study.<br><img src="http://ww2.sinaimg.cn/mw690/72a818edjw1eofrlznkshj20td0iytcl.jpg" alt="My Visualized Resume"></p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>I created my visualized resume through <a href="http://www.wordle.net/" target="_blank" rel="external">Wordle</a>. Yes, I have passion fo]]>
    </summary>
    
      <category term="AboutMe" scheme="http://lianliu.me/tags/AboutMe/"/>
    
      <category term="Color" scheme="http://lianliu.me/tags/Color/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Team Design]]></title>
    <link href="http://lianliu.me/2014/09/29/Team-Design/"/>
    <id>http://lianliu.me/2014/09/29/Team-Design/</id>
    <published>2014-09-29T05:50:54.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-01-20T07:31:17.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is an optional assignment from our Project Management class. The requirements are as follows.</p>
<p>====================================<br>You are professional consultants offering Project Management related services!<br>You are developing a means to communicate Who you are and What you offer!<br>Here are the things we are looking for:</p>
<ul>
<li>Best Team Name </li>
<li>Best Team Logo</li>
<li>Best Team Motto</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="AuroReal">AuroReal</h2>
<h4 id="Team_Members">Team Members</h4>
<p><strong>Team 7</strong>: Akash Gupta, Aaron Shakin, Lian Liu, Mohammad Ali Raahim</p>
<h4 id="About_the_Team">About the Team</h4>
<p>AuroReal is a project management consulting team focused on commercializing programs. We provide start-up, emerging and well-established companies with useful insights for improving their commercialization decisions.<br>Commercialization is one of the most significant stages of the technological innovation process due to its high risks and costs. At AuroReal, we work as advisors as well as your collaborators during this crucial stage to help you avoid errors that could translate into serious market failure.<br>AuroReal is made up of four professional consultants with expertise in Mechanical Engineering, Electrical Engineering, Product Development, Automation and Control Systems. The team has comprehensive experience in technical marketing, digital marketing and intellectual property. We are here to support you taking decisive actions and achieve sustainable results.</p>
<h4 id="About_the_Name">About the Name</h4>
<p>AuroReal comes from Aurora and Realization. The goal of the team is to help companies realize emerging high-tech innovations, as the aurora of our time, into real market shares. </p>
<h4 id="Team_Logo">Team Logo</h4>
<p><img src="http://ww3.sinaimg.cn/mw690/72a818edjw1eofzkbmoo0j22di0qn13y.jpg" alt="AuroReal"><br>AuroReal helps move your business from the Red Ocean to the Blue Ocean and ensures sustainable growth by providing commercialization consulting services.</p>
<h4 id="Team_Mascot">Team Mascot</h4>
<p><img src="http://ww2.sinaimg.cn/mw690/72a818edjw1eofznjhr0xj21pe1l5qd9.jpg" alt="AuroReal Dolphin"><br>The Blue Ocean recalls everyone of this smart animal, dolphin. AuroReal Dolphin represents the team’s knowledge, wisdom and energetic spirit. The smooth design can be easily and clearly applied to different kinds of materials in addition to printing, such as T-shirts, trophies, packages and company giveaways. With no additional accessories AuroReal Dolphin can be designed into 3D samples and the wide back of the dolphin leaves adequate space to print slogans or QR code to deliver more information.</p>
<h4 id="Team_Motto">Team Motto</h4>
<p>We help you realize your technology and win the market as a team. </p>
<h4 id="Designing_Reference:">Designing Reference:</h4>
<p>CG3, Deloitte, Erie Innovation and Commercialization, Caterpillar</p>
<h4 id="About_the_Team-1">About the Team</h4>
<p>All four team members of AuroReal are students from Duke MEMP (Master of Engineering Management Program). The program prepares engineering and science graduates to become future industry leaders.</p>
<p><em>I felt guilty not winning the 100 dollars prize for our team with this design. In general, the concept was comprehensive and creative. But the artwork was a little crude. I wanted to say at that time, I had just been in the US for less than two months. I was content with my achievement of making up all these instructions in English from nothing. But this is life, no excuse. I have to do better next time.</em></p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>This is an optional assignment from our Project Management class. The requirements are as follows.</p>
<p>===============================]]>
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Color" scheme="http://lianliu.me/tags/Color/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[How to Reset Your Network Connection]]></title>
    <link href="http://lianliu.me/2014/09/18/How-to-Reset-Your-Network-Connection/"/>
    <id>http://lianliu.me/2014/09/18/How-to-Reset-Your-Network-Connection/</id>
    <published>2014-09-17T22:14:20.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-01-20T07:20:33.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Spending twenty minutes calling Linksys customer service. Here is what I learned; <em>incase it happens again</em>.<br>BTW, Linksys does have qualified customer service as long as you still have your warranted. </p>
<ul>
<li>Reset your modem: unplug the power for 3 minutes;</li>
<li>Connect the modem to your laptop; </li>
<li>Check IP address: network and sharing centre -&gt; change adapter settings -&gt; Ethernet status;</li>
<li>Connect the modem to the router;</li>
<li>Connect the router’s <strong>OUT port</strong> to your laptop;</li>
<li>Visit 192.168.1.1; leave the user name blank; pswd: admin;</li>
<li>Internet connection type: automatic configuration - DHCP;</li>
<li>Mac Address Clone: Clone PC’s Mac;</li>
<li>Check whether the internet is connected;</li>
<li>Unplug the power of your router to release the IP address;</li>
<li>Status: check your new IP address;</li>
<li>Wireless:<br>  Manually -&gt; network mode: mixed -&gt; Channel width: 20MHz only -&gt; Channel: 6-2.437HZ -&gt; SSID broadcast: enabled;</li>
<li>Wireless security: Set network name and pswd;</li>
<li>Unplug the wire from your laptop;</li>
<li>Check whether you can get online now;</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>Spending twenty minutes calling Linksys customer service. Here is what I learned; <em>incase it happens again</em>.<br>BTW, Linksys does ]]>
    </summary>
    
      <category term="FunFact" scheme="http://lianliu.me/tags/FunFact/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
